现在正在为您披露报道上周在伦敦的袭击事件
We come to you now with revelations about last week's attack
一个匿名消息源提供了这段视频
in London. An anonymous source provided this video.
视频内容为昆汀·贝克 又名神秘客死前的一刻
It shows Quentin Beck, aka.Mysterio, moments before his death.
事先警告 这段视频有可能给您带来不适
A warning, you may find this video disturbing.
我想方设法地把元素众送回他们的维度
I managed to send the Elemental back through the rift but I
但我觉得我没办法活着离开这座桥了
don't think I'm gonna make it out of this bridge alive.
蜘蛛侠不知为何攻击了我
Spider-Man attacked me for some reason. He has
他手握着一只配备斯塔克科技的武装无人机军团
an army of weaponized drones, Stark technology.
他说他才是世界上唯一能成为钢铁侠接班人的人
He's saying he's the only one who's gonna be the new Iron Man, no one else.
是否确认执行无人机攻击指令
Are you sure you want to commence the drone
这会带来很大数量的伤亡
attack? There will be significant casualties.
确认 把他们全部处决掉
Do it. Execute them all.
这个令人大跌眼镜的视频
This shocking video was released earlier today
早些时候发布于争议性新闻网站 号角日报网
on the controversial news website TheDailyBugle.net.
没想到吧 观众们 这下铁证如山了
There you have it, folks, conclusive proof that Spider-Man was responsible
神秘客 一个来自其他次元的 为了保护我们的星球
for the brutal murder of Mysterio, an interdimensional warrior
而牺牲自己 载入史册的世界上最伟大的超级英雄
who gave his life to protect our planet, and who will no doubt
蜘蛛侠将为他的惨死负责
go down in history as the greatest superhero of all time.
但还没完 大伙们
But that's not all, folks.
接下来的才是真正的重磅炸弹 坐好听清楚了
Here's the real blockbuster. Brace yourselves, you might wanna sit down.
蜘蛛侠的...蜘蛛侠的真名...
Spider-Man's real... Spider-Man's real name is...
蜘蛛侠的真名是彼得帕克
Spider-Man's name is Peter Parker.
我了个
What the f---
没错 观众们 彼得帕克 一个十七岁的高中生
That's right, folks. Peter Parker, a seventeen year old high school
居然是一个杀人凶...
delinquent, harboring a homicidal...
你是蜘蛛侠的女朋友吗 你是蜘蛛侠的女朋友吗
Are you Spider-Man's girlfriend? Are you Spider-Man's girlfriend?
- 蜘蛛侠 - 他在这
- Spider-Man! - He's here!
- 喂 请不要碰她 - 原来你只是个小孩
- Whoa, whoa, whoa. Please don't touch her.- You're just a kid?
你谋杀了神秘客 你帮他谋杀了神秘客
You murdered Mysterio? You helped him murder Mysterio?
不 我...我没有
No, I... I didn't...
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
他动手 蜘蛛侠对我动手
He hit me. Spider-Man hit me!
他动手 蜘蛛侠居然对我动手
人民仰仗他 尊称他为英雄
People looked up to this boy and called him a hero.
但我更愿意称呼他为 公众的头号公敌
I'll tell you what I call him: Public Enemy Number One!
我再也不想体验荡蛛丝了
I don't ever wanna do this ever again!
MJ 我很抱歉但你的手挡我脸了我什么都...
MJ, I'm so sorry but I can't see anything with your hand in my...
对不起对不起 现在我们要去哪儿
I'm sorry, I'm sorry. Okay, where are we gonna go?
- 我不知道 你家 - 不 我们不能去我家
- I don't know. Your house. - Oh, no! We can't go to my house.
- 我爸会杀了你 - 啥
- My Dad will kill you! - What?
我以为你说你爸挺喜欢我的
I thought you said your Dad really liked me?
今非昔比了
Yeah, well, not anymore.
- Dude. - Dude!
- Dude! - Dude!
什么...我很抱歉
- Dude! - What... I'm so sorry!
- 你还好吗 - 不 一点也不
- Are you okay? - No, not really.
哟 彼得
Yo, Peter!
我们该走了 快
We should go. We should go. Come on.
- 但你说你不想再荡蛛丝了 - 别废话荡就完了
- But you said you don't wanna swing... - You should just swing me. Yeah.
好吧 我们去搭地铁
Okay. We can take the subway.
小心
Look out!
真是越来越糟了
That was so much worse. Okay.
- 你还好吗 - 还行...还行...
- Are you okay? - Yeah. Yeah...
拜托 拜托 准备好了吗 我很抱歉
Come on, come on, come on. Ready? I'm so sorry.
我真是太蠢了 我都没意识到原来你那么痛苦
I just feel so dumb. I didn't realize you were miserable.
不 其实还挺有意思的不是吗 这个叫什么 萍水相逢
No, it was really fun, alright? You know, that's why call it a fling!
- 况且我们逢了那么久 - 我很开心
- And we flung. - It was fine.
我可以变得更有趣 我也可以成为一个有趣的人
I could've been more fun. I can be fun.
- 有空再约吧 - 什么时候
- We'll hang out again. - Like... when do you think?
- 我应该看看那是什么 - 不 不 不 不 哈皮
- I should see what that is. - No. No, no, no, no. Happy.
- 这是我的工作 - 他总是这样来无影去无踪的...
- It's what I do. - He's always coming and going...
- 彼得 - 不是他...
- Peter?- It's not...
- 彼得 我的天啊彼得...- 噢不不不 我该怎么办才好
- Peter? Oh. God. Peter... - Oh, no. Oh, no. I don't know what to do!
彼得...
Peter...
- 噢噢噢 - 我什么都没看见
- Oh. Oh, no. - We didn't see anything.
- 事情不是看上去这样的 哈皮 - 我很抱歉
- This isn't what it looks like, Happy. - I'm sorry...
- 注意安全就行了... - 事情并不是看上去这样的
- Just practice safe... - It's not what it looks like.
噢 嘿
Oh, hey!
你一定是MJ
You must be MJ!
- 很高兴认识你 - 我也很高兴认识你
- Nice to meet you. - So nice to meet you.
等会儿 你刚刚哭了
Wait, have you been crying?
我们分手了
We broke up.
- 嘿 蜘蛛侠 - 噢
- Hey, Spider-Man! - Oh, uh...
真棒 我都不知道你们分手了 我还以为你真的陷入爱河了 梅
Thank you. I didn't know you guys broke up. I thought you were in love, May.
- 不 我们讨论过这个了 - 我觉得也许我该走了
- No, we talked about this... - I should probably leave, I think...
我一直觉得你们俩很般配...
I thought you guys were such a handsome couple...
- 你懂的 划清界限什么的… - 噢
- You know, it's really about boundaries... - Oh...
- 听着 先进去再说 - 有人按门铃
- Oh, hey, listen. Go in here. - Is that the door?
- 嘿 那个是不是真的… - 先别谈这个
- Hey, is it true about... - Not now!
当自己家就好…
Just make yourself home...
是有关性方面的事 彼得
... about sex, Peter.
这跟性一点关系都没有
This has nothing to do with sex.
看在上帝的份上 如果你先再来一次的话...
God's sakes, it's the goal but if you wanna go over it again...
我的意思是…那是什么声音
I mean, I'm... What's that sound?
嘿 蜘蛛侠
Hey, Spider-Man!
我的意思是 如果你想复合的话我其实很乐意 我只是不想…
I mean, I'm happy to rehash it if you want to. I just don't...
你能不能先别玩手机了
Can you get off your phones for five minutes,
我只是想跟你聊聊我们之间的关系 好吗
I just wanna talk to you about your relationship, okay?
彼得
Peter?
什么
What?
那是… 开什么玩笑
- Is that... - Is that here?
我觉得也许没什么大不了的
I mean maybe it's not such a big deal.
蜘蛛威胁
Spider-Menace!
世界各地的政府开启了对凶手
Governments around the world launched investigations
蜘蛛侠 又名彼得帕克
into the murderer known as Spider-Man,
又名蛛网头 一个数年来威胁纽约市民
aka, Peter Parker, aka, the web-headed war criminal,
生命安全的战犯的调查工作
who for years has been terrorizing the decent citizens of New York.
现在 整座城市和世界都会看到他的真实面目
Well now, this city and the world see him for what he truly is.
一个杀人凶手
Murderer!
上周伦敦毁灭性袭击的新细节现已浮出水面
New details from last week's devastating attack in London have emerged.
更多信息 我们现在去联合情报总部……
For more, we go now to Joint Intelligence Headquarters...
刚刚证实了
... who released just a short while ago confirms,
用于伦敦袭击事件的武装无人机
that the deadly drones used in the London attack,
是斯塔克工业的产品
were designed by Stark Industries.
联邦探员 开门 联邦探员 待在这别动
- Federal agents! Open up! - Federal agents? You stay here!
灾害控制管理部
Department of Damage Control.
我们现在有张关于蜘蛛侠的逮捕令
We have a warrant for the arrest of Peter Parker.
你知道第四修正案吗 当然知道
- You know the fourth amendment? - Sure.
这是不符合情理的搜查和扣押 给我进去 伙计们 动起来
- Unreasonable search and seizure? - Get in here, guys. Let's go.
我没有杀昆廷贝克 是无人机杀的 但是那些无人机是你的
- I didn't kill Quentin Beck. The drones did. - The drones that are yours.
不 听着…
No... Well, look...
尼克弗瑞当时也一直在那儿 你们去问他 他可以解释清楚
Nick Fury was there the entire time. Just ask him and he can explain everything.
尼克弗瑞已经不在地球上一年多了
Nick Fury has been off-planet for the last year.
什么
What?
彼得
Peter!
MJ! Uhh...
他们跟这些事一点关系都没有
They had nothing to do with it, sir!
什么都不要说 我们请了律师 什么都不要说 我们请了律师
- Don't say anything, we got a lawyer. - Don't say anything, we got a lawyer.
我要见律师
I want a lawyer.
琼斯- 沃特森女士…
Miss Jones-Watson...
琼斯 不要加沃特森
Jones. I don't go by Watson.
琼斯女士
Miss Jones...
你为什么想找律师 如果… 如果我没什么可隐瞒的
- Why do you want a lawyer if... - I have nothing to hide?
没错 除非…除非我确实犯了什么事
- Exactly. Unless... - I'm actually guilty of something?
我可太了解你们的话术和我所拥有的司法权利了
I'm very aware of your tactics and my rights.
回答我的问题
Just answer my questions.
我看过你的档案
I've seen your file.
你比她更聪明更年轻 而且有大好前程等着你
You're a smart, young woman with a bright future ahead of her.
为什么你愿意为彼得帕克这样一个义警冒这么大的风险
Why would you risk it all by getting involved with a vigilante like Peter Parker?
很抱歉让你久等了
So sorry to keep you waiting.
能不能给奈德点零食吃 他一直在等
Can we get Ned a snack, please? He's been waiting.
老兄 我真的非常抱歉
Dude, I'm so sorry about that.
我一句话都不能跟你说
I'm not supposed to say anything to you.
不用 奈德 你什么都不用说
No, Ned. Not even a thing.
我只有一个问题
I just have one question...
当MJ告诉你彼得是蜘蛛侠的时候…
When MJ told you that Peter was Spider-Man...
喔喔喔 怎么了
- Whoa, whoa, whoa... - What's up?
我比MJ早知道太久了 我就相当于蜘蛛侠的闺中密友
I knew way before MJ did. I was Spider-Man's guy in the chair.
喔 我知道了
Oh, I know about those.
我的意思是 大多数人都有闺中密友
I mean, half the guys have guys in the chair.
没错 你绝对想不到…
Exactly! You wouldn't know...
我曾经帮他找到了秃鹫
I literally helped him find the Vulture.
这个我倒不知道
I didn't know that.
有一次我还帮他骇进他的战服 还帮他进入了太空
And I helped him hack his suit once, and kinda helped him get to Space.
所以 在蜘蛛侠的非法义警生涯中 你是他的主要同伙
So, in Spider-Man's illegal vigilanteism, you were his main accomplice.
我想把我说的话严格记录在案
I would like to have my words strictly from the record.
无意冒犯
With all due respect,
虽然我的话很不诚恳
and I mean that very insincerely,
但除非你有什么有实证的罪名要指控我们
unless you have some real specific charges to throw at us,
不然从法律上来说 你无权把我们关在这
legally, you can't hold us here.
你绝对要请个律师
You should definitely lawyer up.
你说什么
Excuse me?
危害儿童安全是件非常令人痛恨的事
Child endangerment is a nasty rap.
那个男孩相信你 作为他的法定监护人 作为一个“母亲”
The boy was entrusted to you, and as his legal guardian, essentially his mother,
你不仅允许他做伤害自己的事 你甚至还鼓励他
you not only allowed him to endanger himself, but you actually encouraged it.
哪家父母会那样做
Who does that?
我要见彼得 就现在
I wanna see Peter right now.
斯塔克工业今天卷入了有关蜘蛛侠和神秘客的争议之中
Stark Industries was caught in the web of the Spider-Man/Mysterio controversy today,
联邦探员开始调查失踪的斯塔克工业技术
when federal agents opened an investigation into missing Stark technology.
探员们想知道被拿走的到底是些什么东西
The agents wanna know exactly what was taken...
至少照片上我挺好看
At least they used a good picture.
很好 谢谢
That's great. Thank you.
我有几个好消息 彼得
Well, I have some good news, Peter.
我觉得对你的任何指控都不会成立
I don't believe any of the charges against you are gonna stick.
等等 真的吗 我就知道
- Wait, seriously? - Oh, I knew it.
我的天 默多克先生 谢谢你 太好了
- Oh, my God, Mr. Murdock. Thank you. - Yes.
谢谢你 马特 真是太棒了
- Thank you, Matt. - That's amazing.
是挺完美的 然而...
Well, perfect. However...
霍根先生 是
- Mister Hogan? - Yes?
联邦正在积极调查失踪科技
The feds are actively investigating the missing technology.
我理解你对斯塔克先生和他的遗产的忠心 但如果牵扯到你的话...
I understand you're loyal to Mr. Stark and his legacy, but if you were involved...
如果牵扯到我 你需要请个律师
- If I was involved? - I might secure a lawyer.
我想因为我正在接受调查所以我需要个律师
I need a lawyer because I'm un... I'm under inves... I thought,
你不是说没有指控了吗 那我可不可以说
you said, there's no charge. I could say
我的律师建议我拒绝回答任何问题
under advisement of counsel, I refuse to answer the question
因为...会牵连到我
respectfully because I... the answer could incriminate me.
《好家伙》里面有讲过 《好家伙》里面怎么讲的来着
There's a saying in Goodfellas. What did they say in Goodfellas?
我知道 那个确实有意思...冷静
I know, that's interesting... Calm down.
让我们先听他说 马特
Let's hear what he has to say. Matt?
你需要一个非常厉害的律师
You're gonna need a really good lawyer.
彼得 你也许逃过了司法法庭的制裁 但事情有可能会变得更糟
Peter, you may have dodged your legal troubles, but things will get much worse.
你还要接受社会舆论法庭的审判
There is still the court of public opinion.
你刚刚是怎么做到的
How did you just do that?
我是个很好的律师
I'm a really good lawyer.
我们需要找一个更安全的地方
We're gonna need a safer place to live.
报警系统已停用
Alarm systems, deactivated.
看上去不错...
It looks nice and....
而且很安全
safe.
欢迎来到精神绿洲
Welcome, to the spiritual oasis.
你喜欢大金刚二世吗
You like Donkey Kong Jr.?
噢 哈皮
Oh, Happy.
你的大学申请提交了吗
Did you send in your applications yet?
我刚刚才递交了麻省理工的申请 你呢
I literally just finished my MIT one. You?
一样 想象下如果我两个都被录取了会怎样
- Same. - Imagine if we both got in?
那奈德呢 确实 但...
- And Ned? - Yeah, but...
我们得拿奖学金才能去
We have to take scholarships so we could actually go.
得了吧 你各方面成绩都很不错 而且...
Come on. You got good scores, and good grades, and...
你觉得我太务实了 没没没 好吧...
- You think I'm being too pragmatic. - No, no, no, no. Well...
有一点 没关系
Kind of. That's okay.
那是你身上我最喜欢的一点
That's one of my favorite things about you.
真的 对
- Really? - Yeah.
那其他最喜欢的点呢
Well, what are your other favorite things?
我还喜欢你那近乎无情的乐观
I love your relentless optimism.
是的 我是那种“半瓶醋”的女孩
Yeah. I am a "glass half full" kind of gal.
我真的很喜欢你善与人打交道的性格
I really like how you're a people person.
我爱与人打交道
I love people.
真的很爱
Love 'em... so much.
你也喜欢运动
You like sports.
我觉得今年大都会队会有个好成绩
I think the Mets are gonna go all the way this year.
真的 那是什么声音
- Really? - What's that noise?
噢 是哈皮在打鼾 你看
Oh. That's... that's Happy. Look.
他把房间让给梅了 所以他在这睡
He gave his room to May, so he's sleeping down here.
我有个奇怪的问题想问你
I have a weird question.
对这一切你是否会有一点释怀的感觉
Does any part of you feel relieved about all of this?
自从我被蜘蛛咬了之后...
Ever since I got bit by that Spider...
我大概只过了一周的正常人生活
I've only had one week, where my life has felt normal.
还算正常人的生活 应该
Well, kind of normal, I guess.
然后...
And...
然后直到你发现了我的身份
That was when you found out.
因为 在我生命中我想让他们知道我身份的人
Because then, everyone that was in my life
都知道了我的身份 你懂的
that I wanted to know... you know.
就感觉很完美
And it was perfect.
但现在所有人都知道了 然后...
But now everybody knows. And...
我就成了全世界最出名的人...
I am the most famous person in the entire world...
结果我还是一贫如洗
... and I'm still broke.
我很期待明天能见到你
I'm... excited to see you tomorrow.
我也是
Yeah, me too.
差不多得了
Wrap it up.
你们都很喜欢彼此 大家都知道 把电话挂了
You both like each other. We get it. Hang up.
已经没有新的感情领域可以拓展了 好吗 我要睡了
There's no new ground being broken. Okay? I need my eight hours.
你全程都在偷听是不是
Have you been listening this whole time?
嗨 哈皮
Hi, Happy.
你当我想听啊
Not by choice.
MJ跟你问好
MJ says hi.
你好
Hello.
我们现在报道的是中城高中最有名的学生的高三的第一天
We're covering the first day of senior year for Midtown High's most famous student,
彼得帕克 去吧 老虎
Peter Parker! Go get 'em, Tiger!
或者我应该说 蜘蛛
Or should I say, Spider?
这里的人群数量还在不断地增长
The crowd has continued to grow here all
现在是中城科学学院的早晨
morning long at the Midtown School of Science...
人群似乎分成了两个派系 蜘蛛侠的支持者和反对者
The crowd seems evenly divided between supporters of Spider-Man, and protesters.
MJ 我们爱你MJ 你是不是要给他生蜘蛛小宝宝了
MJ! MJ, we love you. MJ, are you gonna have his spider-babies?
神秘客永垂不朽 你这个凶手
Mysterio forever! Murderer!
退后
- Back off!
你是谁 我是奈德利兹 我是蜘蛛侠的...
- Who are you? - I'm Ned Leeds. I'm Spider-Man's...
你在找彼得帕克的麻吉 没错就是我 闪电汤普森
Peter Parker's best friend. You come at my boy? You come at Flash Thompson.
你想知道我们之间鼓舞人心的友谊是什么样的吗?
You wanna read about our inspiring friendship?
在我的新书《闪点》里可以找到
You can now from my new book, Flashpoint.
一个蜘蛛 心连心 成千上万疯狂的记忆 快来看看
One spider, two hearts, a million crazy-ass memories. Check it out.
快点进去 不 等等
- Go. Go. go. go. Go! - No, wait up...
我们里面见 好吗
I'll see you inside, okay?
继续关注中城新闻 为您带来彼得迄今为止
Keep watching Midtown News all year as we bring you upclose and personal coverage
最大的一场战役：大学入学
of Peter fighting his biggest battle yet: college admissions.
彼得
Peter.
我们很高兴
We would love to...
能欢迎你回来
Welcome you back...
中城高中
To Midtown High.
一个塑造英雄的地方
Where we shape heroes.
嗯嗯 亦或者塑造凶手的地方
- Uh-huh. - Or murderers.
打住
Stop it.
很荣幸为你服务
It's an honor to serve you...
先生 天啊
- Sir. - God!
神秘客是对的
Mysterio was right.
打住 我们不应该.. 没什么
Stop. We don't... that's all.
一部分同学专门为你做了这个
Some of the students put this together for you.
不 是你做的
No. You did that.
你做的 我只不过帮了点小忙而已
- You did that. - I helped a little bit.
我尝试阻止他很多次了 但你居然还是做到了
I tried to stop him so many times, but you piled through.
全是他一个人做的 你干的很棒
- He did all of that. - You did a great job.
我希望你有时间能来看一下
I hope you have time to stop and check it out...
不看直接走人也行
And feel free to walk...
或者 在走廊里荡来荡去也行...爬上天花板避开人群也行
Or, or swing through the hallway... Or crawl on the ceiling to avoid everybody.
我们知道这些你都能做到
We all know you can do it.
我要...
I'm just gonna...
我知道你做了什么
I know what you did.
打住 你这是在丢自己的脸
Stop it. You're embarassing yourself.
他是个阴谋论者
He's a conspiracy theorist.
我们能不能就这样在这待一天
Can we just like, stay up here all day?
下面太疯狂了 等等 这则不错
- It is so crazy down there. - Wait, this one's good.
有人建议说
Some suggest that,
帕克拥有类似于雄性蜘蛛的
Parker's powers include the male spider's
催眠魅惑女性的能力
ability to hypnotize females.
就像他魅惑MJ一样
Which he used to seduce Jones-Watson
让MJ对他产生崇拜
into his cult of personality.
停停停
Stop! Stop.
好的 我的蜘蛛大人
Yes, my Spider-lord.
终于能有点私人空间了
Finally. Some privacy.
下面太疯狂了
It is so crazy down there.
我在想...
So, I was thinking...
等我们进了麻省理工
When we get into MIT,
我们应该同居
we should live together.
当然
Yeah, for sure.
我喜欢这个主意
Yeah. Love that.
我们也可以像这张照片里一样 对
- This is gonna be us. - Yes.
减去玩具飞碟
Minus the frisbee.
还有微笑 麻省理工很明显只是个梦
- And the smiling. - MIT's obviously the dream...
但如果我们都被备选大学录取了
But if we match-up our backup schools,
无论如何 我们都会在波士顿
either way, we'll all be together in Boston.
新学校 新城市 我可以在那里当蜘蛛侠
New school, new town. I can Spider-Man there.
波士顿也有犯罪份子的 对不对
I mean they have crime in Boston, right?
对 肯定有 是啊 邪恶的犯罪分子
- Yes. Yes, they do. - Yeah, wicked crime.
就像一个全新的人生一般
Yeah, so it'll be like a fresh start.
怎么了
What's up?
我不知道 我只是感觉
I don't know. I just feel like if you don't...
如果你对失望有所期待的话
If you expect disappointment,
那你就永远也不会失望了
then you can never really get disappointed.
Come on.
一定会是一个崭新的开始
It'll be a fresh start.
而且我们大家都会在一起
And, we'll all be together.
你是对的
Yeah. You're right.
新的开始
Fresh start.
第一张来了
First one's here!
还好 只是备选学校而已
It's okay. It's a backup school.
彼得
Peter?
不行
No?
最后一个
Last one.
麻省理工
MIT?
好吧
Okay.
准备好了吗 琼斯...
- Ready? - Jones...
我让你把万圣节装饰撤下来...
I told you to take down the Halloween decorations...
事实上 你是让萨沙去撤 所以...
Actually, that was Sasha, so...
给我态度好点 赶紧去做
Enough attitude, just do it.
来了
On it.
我感觉我要吐了 千万别
- I feel like I'm gonna puke. - Well, don't.
你要是吐了 拖地的人是我
Because, he will just make me clean it.
这是我们唯一的机会
This is our only shot.
成败在此一举
It's here, or nowhere.
别这样
Hey! Come on.
你们准备好了吗
Okay. You guys ready?
我数三声
Okay. On three.
一
One...
二
Two...
三
Three...
无了
No.
我也无了 你呢
No. You?
鉴于最近的社会争议
"In light of recent controversy, we are unable to
我们暂不考虑您的入学申请
consider your application at this time."
这不公平
This is so not fair.
这太不公平了 我什么也没做错
I mean, this is so not fair. I didn't do anything wrong.
而且你们更没有做错什么
And you guys definitely didn't do anything wrong.
对失望抱有期望 你就不会感到失望
Expect disappointment, and you will never get disappointed.
找到你们了
Busted!
你们没被录取
You guys didn't get in?
是啊 因为我们真的是蜘蛛侠的朋友
Yeah. Because we're actually friends with Spider-Man.
Uhh, yeah...
我得走了 我还得去见招生主任
I better get going. There's a, mixer for new admissions...
抱歉 伙计们
And... sorry, guys.
琼斯 你在干什么 赶紧去干活
Jones, what are you doing? Get back to work.
来了
Yeah. Coming.
你猜怎么着
You know what?
我什么都不会改变
I wouldn't change a thing.
我也是
Me neither.
但是 我还得把这封信给我爸妈看
Although, I coulda just showed this letter to my parents.
Umm....
Hi.
有人吗
Hi!
我是...
I'm...
世界上最没脑子的人 我知道
The most brainless person in the world. I know.
我是王 注意别滑倒了 我们可没买保险
Wong. Try not to slip. We don't have liability insurance.
你们这是在举办假日派对吗 没有
- Is all this for a holiday party? - No.
这其中一个传送门连接着西伯利亚
One of the rotunda gateways connects to Siberia.
然后雪崩了
Blizzard blasted through.
因为有人忘了施保持封印的咒语
Because someone forgot to cast a maintenance spell to keep the seals tight.
没错他确实忘了 因为他忘了我现在有更重要的职责
That's right. He did. Because he forgot I now have higher duties.
崇高的职责
Higher duties?
至尊法师都有崇高的职责 你没听错
The Sorcerer Supreme has high duties, yes.
慢着 我以为你才是至尊法师
Wait, I thought you were the Sorcerer Supreme?
不 严格意义上来说他才是
No. He got it on a technicality
因为灭霸的响指导致我失踪了五年
'cause I blipped for five years.
恭喜你
Oh. Well, congratulations.
如果我在这 我早就...
If I'd been here, then I'd...
把圣所毁的一塌糊涂了 你两个 不准偷懒
Burned the place down. You two, no one sits.
快点铲
Start shoveling.
所以 彼得
So, Peter...
我能为你做点什么
To what do I owe the pleasure?
对了
Right. Umm...
很抱歉打扰你 先生 但是...
I'm really sorry to bother you, sir, but...
拜托 我们可是一起拯救过宇宙的战友
Please. We saved halfthe universe together.
你叫我先生也太见外了
I think we're beyond calling me sir.
好吧 史蒂芬
Okay, uhh... Stephen.
听起来怪怪的 但我允了
That feels weird, but I'll allow it.
当...
When...
当神秘客揭晓了我的身份之后
When Mysterio revealed my identity...
我的人生就被搞得一团糟
My entire life got screwed up, and...
我在想 我的意思是 我不知道能不能行
I was wondering, I mean, I don't even know if this would actually work,
但是我想也许
but I was wondering if...
也许你可以时空回溯然后抹去他的所作所为
Maybe you could go back in time and make it so that he never did?
彼得
Peter...
为了复活 我们已经篡改了时空的稳定性
we tampered with the stability of space-time to resurrect
那可是无数人的生命 现在就因为你的生活被打乱了 所以你想重蹈覆辙
countless lives. You wanna do it again now just because yours got messy?
这...这不仅仅是我的事 还伤害到了许多人
This isn't... it's not about me. I mean, this is really hurting a lot of people.
我的...
My...
我的梅姨 哈皮
My Aunt May, Happy...
我的麻吉 我女朋友 他们的未来都被毁了
My best friend, my girlfriend, their futures
就因为他们知道我是蜘蛛侠 更何况
are ruined just because they know me, and...
他们什么也没做错
They've done nothing wrong.
我很抱歉 但是
I am so sorry, but...
就算我想帮你
even if I wanted to...
但我也已经没有时间宝石了
I don't have the Time Stone anymore.
也对噢
That's right.
如果我耽误了你的时间
I'm really sorry if I...
我很抱歉
wasted your time.
你没有... 那就算了吧
-You didn't... - Just forget about it.
他会的 他确实很擅长忘记某些事情
He will. He's really good at forgetting things.
王 你给了我很大的启发
Wong. You've actually generated a good idea.
什么
What?
卡夫卡符文
The runes of Cafkal.
卡夫卡的符文
噢 只是一个再普通不过的遗忘咒罢了
Oh, it's just a standard spell of forgetting.
虽然没法时空回溯 但至少人们会忘记你曾是蜘蛛侠的事实
Won't turn back time, but at least people will forget that you were ever Spider-Man.
你确定吗 不 我不太确定
- Seriously? - No. Not seriously.
这个咒语穿梭于已知与未知的现实之间的黑暗边界
That spell travels the dark borders between known and unknown reality.
太危险了
It's too dangerous.
天啊 我们已经基本不用这个咒语了
God, we've used it for a lot less.
你还记不记得卡玛泰姬的满月派对
Do you remember the full moon party in Kamar-Taj?
不记得 那不就对了
- No. - Exactly.
Come on. Wong.
你还嫌他经历的不够多吗
Hasn't he been through enough?
反正别把我扯进来就行了
Just leave me out of this.
行
Fine.
所以这是什么地方
So what is this place?
至圣所建立在宇宙能量流的交汇之处
The Sanctum's built at the intersection of cosmic energy currents.
我们是第一批找寻宇宙能量之人
We were the first to seek them out.
这些墙壁已经有近千年的历史了
Some of these walls are thousands of years old.
80年代还有人来这拍了集《伸冤人》
And they shot an episode of Equalizer here in the 80's.
Well, I, umm...
我真的很感谢你为我所做的一切 先生
really appreciate you doing this for me, sir.
小事不值一提
Don't mention it.
不要叫我先生
And don't call me sir.
对 抱歉
Right. Sorry.
你准备好了吗
You ready?
准备好了
I'm ready.
很高兴认识你 蜘蛛侠
Nice knowing you, Spider-Man.
等等 你说什么
Wait, excuse me?
整个世界都将忘记彼得帕克是蜘蛛侠这件事
The entire world is about to forget that Peter Parker is Spider-Man.
包括我 所有人
- Including me. - Everyone?
就不能留一些人知道 咒语可做不到这一点
- Can't some people still know? - That's not how the spell works.
在施法过程中改变咒语是非常困难和危险的
Very difficult and dangerous to change it mid-casting.
所以我的女朋友会忘记我们所经历的一切
So my girlfriend is just gonna forget about everything we've
那事毕之后她还是不是我女朋友
been through? I mean, is she even gonna be my girlfriend?
看情况 取决于她是因为你是蜘蛛侠才做你女朋友 还是...
That depends. Was she your girlfriend just because you're Spider-Man, or...
我不知道 我希望不是
I don't know. I really hope not.
好吧
Alright. Fine.
世界上的每个人都将忘记你是蜘蛛侠
Everyone in the world is gonna forget you're Spider-Man,
除了你女朋友
except your girlfriend.
太感谢了 我的天 奈德
Thank you so much.... Oh, my God. Ned.
奈德 奈德是个什么东西
- Ned! - What is a Ned?
他是我最好的朋友 他知不知道对我来说很重要
He's my best friend so it's really important to me that Ned knows.
好吧 我要施咒了 从现在开始不要改来改去了
Okay. Let's not change the parameters of the spell anymore...
好的 没别的了 我发誓没别的了
- While I'm casting it. - Okay, I'm done. I swear I'm done.
但我的梅姨总该知道吧
But my Aunt May should really know.
彼得 不要干扰我施法
Peter, stop tampering with the spell.
自从她知道我是蜘蛛侠以后 那可真的是一团糟
Once she found out that I was Spider-Man, it was really messy, and
我不觉得我想再经历一次了
I don't think that I can go through with that again.
所以 梅姨可以吗 可以
- So, my Aunt May? - Yes!
噢 谢谢 你开心吗 不 我快烦死了
- Oh, thank you. Happy? - No. I am annoyed.
不 这是个昵称 哈罗德哈皮霍根
No, it's a nickname. Harold "Happy" Hogan.
他以前为托尼斯塔克工作
He used to work for Tony Stark....
您能不能不要再碎碎念了
Could you just stop talking?
其实 以前就知道我是蜘蛛侠的人现在也应该继续知道
Basically, everyone who knew that I was Spider-Man before, should still know.
成功了吗 没有
- Did it work? - No.
我的咒语被你改变了整整六次 五次
- You changed my spell six times. - Five times.
你改了我的咒语 我告诉你 不要那样做
You changed my spell. You don't do that. I told you,
这就是原因
and that is why.
如果我没有及时打住的话 那个咒语就完完全全失控了
That spell was completely out of control. If I hadn't shut it down,
有可能会发生什么灾难性的事情
something catastrophic could've happened.
史蒂芬 我真的很抱歉
Stephen, listen, I am so sorry...
叫我先生
Call me sir.
对不起 先生
Sorry, sir.
你知道吗 即使在我们经历了那么多事情以后
You know, after everything we've been through together, somehow I always forget...
我还是会忘记你只是个孩子
You're just a kid.
听着 很大一部分的问题
Look, part of the problem,
并不在神秘客身上
it's not Mysterio.
而是在你自己身上 你想过两种不同的人生
It's you. Trying to live two different lives.
你越这么想越这么做 就越危险 相信我
And the longer you do that, the more dangerous it becomes. Believe me.
我真的很同情你和你的朋友没法进入大学
I'm so sorry about, you and your friends,
如果他们拒绝了你
not getting into college, but if they rejected you, and...
你就去说服他们 这是你唯一能做的事情
you try to convince them to reconsider, there is nothing else you can do.
你说“说服他们”
When you say "convince them",
你的意思是 让我给他们打电话
you mean like, I could've called them?
是的
Yeah.
可以吗
I can do that?
你没打过是不是
You haven't called?
我 我收到了来信 我以为
Well, I mean, I got their letter, and I assumed that...
等等 你是在跟我说
I'm sorry, but are you telling me,
在你来找我 让我洗脑全世界之前
that you didn't even think to plead your case with them first,
你都还没有找校方谈过这个问题
before you asked me to
是不是
brainwash the entire world?
当你在和我同样处境的时候...
I mean, when you put it like that, then...
拜托 接电话接电话
Come on. Pick up, pick up, pick up...
老兄 干嘛 我很忙唉 闪电 麻省理工的联欢会在哪
- Dude, what? I'm busy. - Flash, where's the MIT mixer?
为什么问这个
Why?
因为我需要找麻省理工的人谈谈
Because, I need to come and talk to someone. I'm
让她给奈德和MJ一个入学的机会
trying to get Ned and MJ a second chance at getting in.
关我什么事
What's in it for me?
我光跟你打电话就已经冒了很大的风险了
I'm risking a lot just talking to you.
好吧 那我...
Okay. I will....
荡蛛丝送你上一个礼拜的学
Pick you up and swing you to school for a week?
一个月
For a month.
一个礼拜
For a week.
两个礼拜 闪电 拜托 帮帮我
- Two weeks. - Flash, please. Come on, help me.
好吧 我会告诉所有人你是我最好的朋友
Okay, I'll tell everyone that you're my best friend.
闪电 帮帮我
Flash, please help me.
好吧好吧好吧
Cool, cool, cool.
这个女的 她是副校长助理 你可以去找她
So there's this lady. The assistant vice chancellor. You can plead your case with her.
太好了 完美 她在哪儿
Okay, perfect. Where is she?
她走了 去哪儿了
- She left. - To go where?
机场
To the airport.
史塔克网络不可用
Stark Network, unavailable.
面部识别不可用
Facial recognition, unavailable.
Hi.
我能看见你
Yep. I can see you.
妈妈
Mom?
Okay.
Yeah.
你好 我是彼得帕克 你知不知道你现在正站在大马路上
- Hi. I'm Peter Parker... - You do know you're in the street, right?
我知道 我很抱歉 但我真的需要跟你谈谈
Yeah, I know. I'm sorry. I just, I really needed to
我知道你现在要去机场
talk to you, I know you're on your way to the airport...
MJ沃特森和奈德利兹是我这辈子遇到过的最聪明的两个人
MJ Watson and Ned Leeds are the two smartest people I've ever met in my entire life,
而我则是个大傻瓜 因为...
and I'm the dumbest person, because....
我让他们帮我 但如果我不让他们帮我的话
I let them help me, but if I didn't let them help
好几百万人都会死 所以拜托...
me, then millions of people would've died, so please...
不要让麻省理工变得和我一样傻瓜 麻省理工傻瓜
- Don't let MIT be dumb like me. - MIT is dumb?
没有 我没说麻省理工傻瓜
No! I'm saying don't let MIT be dumb.
我的意思是
I mean, like the...
那个不让他们帮忙的
the dumber version of me that
那个傻瓜的我
wouldn't have let them help.
你这份说辞是不是没事先排练过 彼得
You didn't rehearse that, did you, Peter?
总之 我想说的是...
Basically, what I'm trying to...
你跑什么 什么...
Why are you running? What...
我的老天爷 女士 你最好赶紧从车里出来
Oh, my God. Ma'am? You should get out of the car.
所有人离开大桥
Everybody get off the bridge!
我们被锁住了 这门
We're locked. Doors --- hey!
你好 彼得
Hello, Peter.
你好
Hi?
我们...我认识你吗 你对我的机器做了什么
- Have we... Do I know you? - What have you done with my machine?
Your ma...
我根本不知道你在说什么 什么机器
I don't know what you're talking about. What machine?
我掌中的太阳能量 没了
The power of the sun, in the palm of my hand. It's gone.
听着 先生 能不能先不要砸车了
Listen, sir. If you stop smashing cars,
我们可以合作 找回你的机器
we could work together and I can help you find your machine.
你是不是想耍我
You wanna play games?
接住
Catch!
没事的 你们很安全 快离开这儿
It's okay. You guys are fine, you're safe. Get out of here.
你觉得你那花哨的新战服能救得了你
You think your fancy new suit's gonna save you?
当时我就应该杀了你的小女朋友
I should've killed your little girlfriend when I had the chance.
你刚刚说什么
What did you just say?
看来我们有竞争对手了
Looks like we got competition.
彼得 救命
Peter! Help!
别担心 女士 我来了
Don't worry, Ma'am! I'm coming!
彼得
Peter!
冷静点 女士
Ma'am, just stay calm.
深呼吸 你还好吗 不
- Just take a deep breath. Are you okay? - No!
一切尽在掌控之中
I've got it all under control.
战服损毁
Suit compromised.
纳米科技
Nanotechnology.
你比我想象的还要厉害 彼得
You've outdone yourself, Peter.
我低估你了
I underestimated you.
但现在 你死定了
But now, you die.
你不是彼得帕克
You're not Peter Parker.
我现在有点混乱
I am so confused right now.
发生什么了 检测到新设备
- What's happening? - New device detected.
正在适配新设备
Pairing new device.
不要听他的 听我的
Don't listen to him, you listen to me.
Hey.
嘿 听我的
Hey. Hey! Listen to me.
不 不是他 是我
No, not him. Me!
你还好吗女士 快 也许还能赶上飞机
Ma'am are you okay? Come on, you can still make your flight.
彼得
Peter.
你是个英雄
You're a hero.
不 我...
No. Well, I'm...
我...
No, I'm...
我会去跟招生处聊聊你的朋友
I'm gonna talk to admissions about your friends,
我还要跟他们聊聊你
and I'm gonna talk to them about you.
不 女士 这和我没关系
No, but, Ma'am, this isn't about me.
我要跟他们聊聊关于你的朋友和你
I'm going to talk to them about your friends, and you.
好吗 真的
- Okay? - Really?
而且如果你别再做啥坏事的话
And if you keep your noses clean,
也许你也有机会进麻省
maybe you'll have a fair shot.
让开我 让我去找那个人
Here. Get out of the way. Let me get that man.
你 我看见你了
You. I see you.
给我过来
Come here!
这一点也不好
That was not okay.
不可理喻
Unbelievable.
在你不再想杀我之前
Until you stop trying to kill me,
你都受我控制 伙计
I'm in control, buddy.
我控制着你背后的那些触手
Of this whole tentacle situation you got going on here.
懂了吗 现在告诉我你是谁 什么情况...
Okay? Now, who are you? What is going on...
奥斯本
Osborn?
博士...
Doctor...
小心你自己许的愿 帕克
Be careful what you wish for, Parker.
让我出去
Let me out of here!
你能给我解释下发生什么了吗
Can you please explain to me what is going on?
你搞砸的那个咒语
That little spell that you botched where you wanted everyone to forget
那个想让所有人忘记彼得帕克是蜘蛛侠的咒语
that Peter Parker is Spider-Man, it started pulling in everyone who knows
正在开始把每个宇宙知道蜘蛛侠是彼得帕克的人全拖进来
Peter Parker is Spider-Man, from every universe.
每个宇宙
From every universe?
你是谁 我在哪儿
Who are you? Where am I?
我觉得我们最好不要跟他接触
I think it's better if we don't with him because, frankly,
因为老实说 多元宇宙是一个
the Multiverse is a concept about which we know
我们知之甚少的概念
frighteningly little.
多元宇宙是真的
The multiverse is real.
这根本不可能
This shouldn't even be possible.
但我以为你不是叫停了那个咒语么
But I thought you stopped the spell?
确实 我控制住了 但还是有几只漏网之鱼
No, I contained it, but it would appear that a few of them squeaked through.
自从你走后 我开始感知到一些来自其他宇宙的存在
After you left, I detected an otherworldly presence.
于是我追到了下水道 找到了这个黏糊糊绿油油的家伙
I pursued it into the sewers, where I found that slimy, green, son of a gun.
咒语
Spell?
是魔法吗
Is it magic?
这是什么意思 生日派对
What is this, a birthday party?
这个小丑是谁
Who is this clown?
这到底是怎么回事儿
What is this madness?
看好了 你知道彼得帕克是蜘蛛侠吗
Watch this. Do you know a Peter Parker who is Spider-Man?
知道
Yes.
是他吗 不是
- Is that him? - No.
看见没有
See?
好吧 接下来我们这么做
Okay, here's what we gotta do.
我不知道接下来我们还要面对
I don't know how many of these
多少个这样的访客 我有看见过一个
- visitors we got... - I saw another one.
在大桥上
On the bridge.
他就像
He was like a...
一只飞着的绿妖精
Like a flying green elf.
听起来有意思 你为什么不从他开始着手
Well he sounds jolly. Why don't you start with him?
在他们摧毁我们的现实之前
I need you to capture them and bring them here,
我需要你把他们抓回来这里
while I figure out how to get them back.
而我留在这思考如何把他们送回去 更重要的是
Before they destroy the fabric of reality, or worse,
不要被王发现
Wong finds out.
奇异博士
Uhh, Doctor Strange?
什么
What?
我的朋友刚刚获得第二次进入麻省理工的机会
My friends and I just got a second chance at getting into MIT.
要是被学校看见我和这些疯怪物打架的话
If the school sees me fighting these...
嘿 积点口德
- crazy monsters, - Hey, watch your mouth!
抱歉 现在是跟我聊大学入学的合适时机吗
- I'm sorry. - You're seriously still talking about college?
你刚刚在干什么
Hey, what did you just do?
这个
This.
你是怎么做到的
How did you do that?
好多生日派对
Lots of birthday parties.
Hey!
只需一发 就可以把他们送来这儿 不用谢
One shot, send it to me and move on. You're welcome.
开始干活吧
Get to work.
先生
Sir?
又咋了
Now what?
我知道这是我捅的篓子 所以我向你保证
I know this is my mess, and I swear to you
我会解决这一切的 但我需要点帮助
that I'll fix it, but I'm gonna need some help.
我不敢相信我居然在至圣所里
I can't believe I'm in the Sanctum Sanctorum.
我也是
Neither can I.
So...
你是怎么知道你有魔法天赋的 因为我奶奶说我们有时候
How did you know you're made of magic? Because my nanna says that we have it in
可以在手上变出点叮铃铃的东西
and sometimes I get these tinglings in my hand...
你该去看精神科医生了
You should talk to your physician.
彼得
Peter!
- Hey! - Hey.
我很抱歉又把你们扯进来 你们得帮我找到这几个人
I'm so sorry for dragging you in this, you just gotta help me find these guys...
没必要道歉 你帮我们争取到了麻省理工的第二次机会
You don't have to apologize. You got us a second shot at MIT.
所以那些坏人是怎么来到我们世界的
So, how did the bad guys get here?
为了把你们搞进大学 他搞砸了一个符咒
He screwed up a spell trying to get you into college.
等等 什么 我以为是魔法镭射 你会使魔法了
- Wait, what? I thought it was a magic laser? - You did it with magic?
不 那是之后的事了 我们先专注于好消息 好吗
No, that was after. Let's just focus on the good news, okay?
不 我们先专注于坏消息
No, let's just focus on the bad news.
目前来说
As of now, you have detected
探测到了0个多元闯入者 所以
zero multiversal trespassers, so...
去拿你的手机
Get on your phones,
搜索互联网 然后
scour the internet, and...
解决这档子破事
Scooby-Doo this shit!
你在这里指点江山
You're telling us what to do,
可明明就是你的咒语
even though it was your spell,
是你搞砸了这一切 这是你的烂摊子
that got screwed up. Meaning that all of this is kind of your mess.
你知道吗
You know, I know
其实我自己也懂一两个咒语 但都是以“请”开头的
a couple of magic words myself, starting with the word 'please'.
请你们 解决这档子破事
Please, Scooby-Doo this shit.
你们可以在地下室工作
You can work in the undercroft.
地下室
The undercroft?
酷毙了
Badass.
伙计们 听着 这个咒语...
Guys, listen. About this whole spell thing...
没什么大不了的
It's totally okay.
真的吗
- Wait, really? - Yeah.
我都懂 你只是想...
I mean, I get it. You were...
拨乱反正...
just trying to fix things...
所以...
And so...
下次记得提前通知我们一声
Maybe just run it by us next time, you know?
因为当你想干点打破宇宙维度之类的事情的时候
That way, when you're thinking, "Hey, I'm about to do something that could...
我们可以帮你
break the universe", we could like, help you.
帮你改造装备之类的 或者
Workshop something, or...
帮你出主意
brainstorm ideas.
成交
Deal.
奈德
Ned?
伙计 我才不在乎 说实话 没什么大不了的
Oh, dude. I don't care. And seriously, not a big deal.
刑架
A torture rack.
那个是普拉提瑜伽机
That is a pilates machine.
这个是... 地窖
- That is... - The crypt.
好了 现在我们找到剩下的人
Okay, so we get the rest of the guys.
你网住他们 魔法博士送他们回去
You zap them, Doctor Magic will send them back.
然后我们进麻省理工
And when we get into MIT,
谁要吃甜甜圈 我请客
round of stale donuts, my treat.
让我们来抓点多元宇宙的人吧
Let's catch some multiverse men.
这两个家伙是谁
Hey! Who the hell are these two?
我的朋友 MJ和奈德
These are my friends. This is MJ and this is Ned.
你好
Hello.
抱歉 你叫啥来着
I'm sorry, what was your name again?
奥托 奥克塔维思博士
Dr. Otto Octavius.
开玩笑吧 你的真名是什么
Wait, no seriously, what's your actual name?
那是只恐龙吗
Oh, is that a dinosaur?
不不不 不可能
No, no, no, May.
我们得先找到这些人
We gotta find these guys first.
快去完成你的任务 然后再回来
Well, finish your mission, then come by.
我找到了
I got one, I got one, I got one.
梅 我得走了 好 爱你 再见
- Oh, May? I gotta go. - Okay. Love you. Bye.
你可以把人从椅子上拉起来
I mean you can take the guy out of the chair
但你没法把椅子从人身上拉出来
but you can't take\ the chair out of the guy.
你找到什么了
What did you find?
有个...
There's a...
城外一处军事研究设施附近发生了骚乱
disturbance near a military research facility outside of the city.
有目击者声称看见一个怪物在天上飞
And witnesses say they saw a monster flying through the air.
肯定是我在大桥上看见的那个人
That's gotta be the guy I saw on the bridge, right?
不可能
That's impossible.
你是不是认识他
You know him, don't you?
在桥上的时候你叫了他的名字
On the bridge, you said his name.
诺曼奥斯本
Norman Osborn.
天才科学家
Brilliant scientist.
军工科学家
Military researcher.
但他太贪婪了
But he was greedy.
走错了路
Misguided.
他怎么了 我们已经受够了你那没完没了的问题了
- What happened to him? - We tire of your questions, boy!
Okay...
我得走了 我们要去哪儿
I gotta go. Where are we going?
不可能是他
It can't be him.
为什么
Why?
因为诺曼奥斯本一年前就死了
Because Norman Osborn died years ago.
所以这个要么是其他东西
So either we saw someone else,
要么就是鬼魂
or you're flying out into the darkness, to fight a ghost.
盯紧那些树 我们还不知道那个人在哪儿
Keep an eye out on those trees, we don't really know where this guy is.
我真不知道你是怎么在这种情况下还能不吐的
I really don't know how you do this without throwing up.
你们看见了吗
Did you guys see that?
没有
No.
这里真的超级黑
It's, it's really dark.
发生什么了
What's happening?
彼得 怎么了
Peter, what is it?
是你的蜘蛛感应
Are you getting the tingle thing?
蜘蛛感应起作用了 是不是
Is the tingle thing happening? Is your tingle tingling?
你们看见了吗
Are you guys seeing this?
看见了 奥斯本
- Yeah. - Osborn?
不 他是绿的 这家伙是蓝的
No. He was green. This guy's blue.
你不会碰巧是从其他宇宙来的吧
You wouldn't happen to be from another universe, would you?
他在干嘛
What's he doing?
我不知道 看上去像是在充电
I don't know. Looks like he's charging.
我不喜欢这样 快网住他
I don't like this. Just web him.
往左 往左
Go left, left! Go left!
等等 右 右
Wait! Right, right!
伙计们
Guys!
你们根本没在帮忙
This is not helping!
不不不 发生什么了
No, no, no. What happened?
彼得 彼得
Peter? Peter?
Whoa.
彼得 是我 弗林特马可 你还记得吗
Peter, it's me. Flint Marko. You remember?
我是彼得 但我不是你宇宙的那个彼得
I'm Peter, but I'm not your Peter.
你不是我宇宙的彼得 什么意思
What do you mean you're not my Peter? What the hell is going on?
我会解释的 但首先你能不能先帮我阻止这家伙
I'll explain everything, but first can you help me stop this guy?
Okay.
你试着包围他 然后我去拔插头
You try to surround him and I'll pull the plug.
好 我们上吧
All right, let's go.
我没办法拖住他很久
I can't hold him much longer.
我抓住了
I got him. I got it.
不同的彼得 真奇怪
Different Peter. Weird.
谢谢
Thanks.
抱歉
Sorry.
别担心
Don't worry about it.
我的肉身居然回来了
I got my body back.
Hey, umm...
这听起来会很扯 但你现在所处的不是你那个的宇宙
This is gonna sound really crazy, but this isn't your universe.
另一个宇宙
Another universe?
什么 我刚刚就有这种感觉
- What? - That's what I was feeling.
力量 截然不同的力量
The power. It's different.
我挺喜欢
I like it.
放轻松 伙计
Easy, buddy.
你们来到这儿事实上是我的错
It's actually my fault that you're here.
来到这宇宙 还是树林
Like the universe? Or the woods?
我讨厌树林 我说的是宇宙 先生
- I hate the woods. - I meant the universe, sir.
所以 你们就打算站在那里 假装没看见我光着屁股吗?
So what? You guys just gonna stand there and act like I ain't butt-ass naked?
没错 啊 没有
- I am. - Uhh, no, no...
那是什么 你刚刚对他做了什么
What was that? What did you just do to him?
没事的 放心
No, no, no. It's okay.
你刚刚是不是把他杀了
Did you kill him?
听着 我可以解释所有事 但请你得先相信我
Whoa, listen. I can explain everything. You just have to trust me, please.
我不相信你 我又不认识你
I don't trust you. I don't know you.
这是什么
What is this?
你站错队了
You picked the wrong side.
康纳斯
Connors?
什么
What?
你认识这个生物
You know this creature?
不不不 他不是生物 他是人
No, no, no, no. Not a creature. A man.
我们来自同一宇宙
From same universes.
柯特康纳斯博士 我在奥斯本企业上班的时候他是那儿的一名科学家
Dr. Curt Connors. He was a scientist in Oscorp when I worked there.
一名出色的科学家
A brilliant scientist.
直到他把自己变成了一只大蜥蜴
Till he turned himself into a lizard. Then he tried
他甚至还想把全城人都变成蜥蜴 真是疯了
to turn the whole city into lizards. It was crazy.
我没有疯 麦克斯 这是人类进化的必要过程
It wasn't crazy, Max. It was the next step in human evolution.
恐龙居然讲话了
The dinosaur can talk.
蜥蜴 好吧
- Lizard. - Right.
话说回来 你是什么情况
Speaking of which, what happened to you? Last I
我记得你以前是个烂牙齿 戴眼镜的谢顶男
recall, you had bad teeth, glasses and a comb-over.
你是不是整容了
Did you get a makeover?
你知道我可以给你整一个真正的容
You know I can give you a real makeover.
让我猜猜 整成一只蜥蜴 没错- Let me guess. Into a lizard?
- Exactly.
你们俩能不能消停会 我们这是在哪儿
Could you two just shut up? Where are we?
一言难尽 一个巫师的地牢
- It's complicated. - A wizard's dungeon.
巫师...巫师的地牢
Wizard's... Wizard's dungeon?
没什么好掩饰的
There's no real way to sugarcoat that.
这就是巫师的地牢
It's literally the dungeon of a wizard.
听着 你可以留着你的魔法
Look, you can keep your magic.
我想试试看刚刚我感受到的那股力量
I want a taste of that new energy I just felt.
彼得 嘿
Oh, Peter. Hey.
那些人到了吗
Hey. Did those guys come through yet?
应该有一个电人和一个沙人
There should be an electric guy and a sand guy.
来了 他们都到了且被关起来了
Yeah. They're all here and locked up.
太好了 我正要在这呆一会儿
Perfect. I'm gonna just stay here for a bit, and try
修复一下我刚刚造成的破坏 不然他们又要怪我了
to fix this damage so they don't blame it on me again.
- Okay. - Hey, I...
没有你 这些我都办不到 所以
I couldn't do any of this without you, so...
谢谢你 当然
- Thank you. - Yeah, of course.
帮我问问那个人到底是颗树变成的怪兽
Hey, ask him if this is like a tree monster,
还是个科学家变成了颗树
or like a scientist that turned into a tree.
这是颗树吗
Is this a tree, man?
这就是颗树
That's a tree.
你个懦夫 现在有一个新的世界等待我们去征服
Coward. We have a new world to conquer.
你让我感到恶心 求求你不要打扰我
- You make me sick. - Leave me alone. Please.
一直躲在阴影之下
Hiding in the shadows...
一直躲避真实的自己
Hiding from who you truly are.
不
No!
你无法逃避你自己
You can't escape yourself!
嘿 梅 嘿 彼得
- Hey, May. - Hey, Peter.
我在上班呢 然后
I'm at work, and, umm...
你在找的其中一个人刚刚走了进来
One of the guys you're looking for just walked in.
梅 请问梅在哪儿 谢谢你
May? Where's May? Thank you.
嘿 他来了
Hey, here he is.
诺曼
Norman,
这是我的侄子
this is my nephew.
诺曼奥斯本
Norman Osborn?
我以为你已经...
I thought that you were...
我在这里的广告上看见了蜘蛛侠
I saw Spider-Man in an ad for this place.
我觉得他可以帮到我
And I thought he could help me.
但你不是他
But you're not him.
等等 你想要蜘蛛侠帮你
Wait, so you want Spider-Man's help?
他慢悠悠的就走进来了
He just wandered in.
我不知道还有哪儿可以去
I didn't know where else to go.
有其他人住在我的家里
Someone's living in my house.
而且奥斯本公司根本就不存在
Oscorp doesn't exist.
我的儿子
My son...
有些时候
Sometimes,
我感觉我不是我自己
I'm not myself.
我是
I'm...
其他人
someone else.
每当他控制我的身体的时候 我就什么都记不起来
And, everytime he's in control, I can't remember.
而现在 我在这个地方 这座城市
And now, I'm here, in this place, in this city,
我不知道
and I don't know...
我不知道我身上发生了什么
I don't know what's going on with me.
我不...这听起来不合常理
I don't... It doesn't make sense.
他迷失了
He's lost.
我不单单说的是在这个宇宙迷路了
And I don't mean just in the cosmos.
他自己的思想也迷失了
I mean in his mind.
他们全都像这样吗
Are they all like this?
对
Yeah.
我的意思是 他们本身或多或少都有点精神上或身体上的问题
Well, I mean they all have their own, mental or physical issues.
他需要帮助 也许他们所有人都需要帮助
Well, he needs help, but maybe they all do.
你不是说...不对 梅
What, you don't mean... No, May, this...
这不关我的事
This isn't my problem.
彼得 真的不关你的事吗
Peter, not your problem? Mmm?
梅
May...
他们回到原来的地方能得到帮助的机会要大得多
Their chance of getting help is way better back where they came from.
送他们回家
Sending them home,
这已经是我们能为他们做的最好的事情了
That's the best thing that we can do for them.
为他们
For them?
还是为你自己
Or for yourself?
看看你周围
Look around you.
这才是我们应该做的
This is what we do.
帮助他人
We help people.
这才是对他们来说最好的
This is what's best, for them.
相信我
Trust me.
但事实依然存在
But the fact remains,
蜘蛛侠依然是个威胁
Spider-Man is a menace!
马上回来
We'll be right back, after a brief word from
先播一段号角牌补充剂广告
Daily Bugle supplements.
另一个你的每日所需
The only other Daily fix you need.
完毕
And, we're out.
说
What?
我盯上他们了
I got eyes on them.
他跟他阿姨和一个我不认识的人在一起
He's with his aunt and some guy I don't know.
你确定
You sure?
他们刚刚离开收容所
They're just leaving the shelter.
好 不要跟丢了
Okay. Don't lose him.
谢谢 梅
Thanks, May.
希望能再次见到你
Hope to see you again.
Hey.
他信任你
He trusts you.
我也是
So do I.
谢谢你把我的战服洗干净了
Thanks for cleaning my suit.
待会儿见
I'll see you later.
伙计们 这个是奥斯本先生 嘿 博士
- Guys, this is Mr. Osborn. - Hey, it's Doctor.
不好意思
Sorry. Umm...
奥斯本博士 这些是我的朋友 奈德和MJ
Dr. Osborn, these are my friends, Ned and MJ.
玛丽简
Mary Jane?
其实是米歇尔琼斯
It's Michelle Jones, actually.
挺迷人的名字
Fascinating.
你觉得这个世界上有没有另一个奈德利兹
Do you think there are other Ned Leedses?
奥克塔维思
Octavius?
奥斯本
Osborn?
你怎么了 发生了...
- What... What happened to you? - What happened to...
你就是一具行尸走肉 你什么意思
- You're the walking corpse. - What do you mean?
你已经死了 诺曼
You died, Norman.
一年前
Years ago.
你疯了
You're insane.
天 我太喜欢这里了
God, I love it here.
你到底在说什么
What are you talking about?
他就活生生的站在那儿
He's standing right there.
他没... 死
- He's not... - Dead.
他俩都在和蜘蛛侠争斗的过程中死了
They both died. Fighting Spider-Man.
新闻上到处都是
It was all over the news.
绿魔
Green Goblin?
被他自己的滑翔机刺穿身体而死
Impaled by the glider he flew around on.
两年后
And a couple of years later...
就是你 章鱼博士
You. Doc Ock.
你和你的机器一起坠入了河底
Drowned in the river with your machine.
一派胡言
That's nonsense.
蜘蛛侠当时想关掉我的聚变反应堆
Spider-Man was trying to stop my fusion reactor.
然后我阻止了他
So I stopped him.
我抓住他了 正中喉咙 然后...
I had him, by the throat.... And then, I...
然后我就在这儿了
And then I was here.
拜托 我告诉你件事
Oh, please. Let me tell you something.
我把蜘蛛侠胖揍了一顿 不信你去问蜘蛛侠
I was whooping Spider-Man's ass. He'll tell you.
然后蜘蛛侠引起电力过载 导致我被困在了电网里
And then he caused an overload. I was stuck in the grid,
吸收数据 正当我快要转变成纯能量的时候
absorbing data. I was about to turn into pure energy,
然后
and then...
然后...靠
And then... Oh, shit.
我就快死了
I was about to die.
麦克斯 你知不知道我死了没有
Max, do you know? Do I die?
太棒了 你又抓住了一个 不 等等 斯特兰奇 他没有威胁
- Oh, great. You caught another one. - No, wait. Strange, he's not dangerous.
没事的
It's okay.
那是什么
What is that?
古老的遗物 梅山帝之盒
It's an ancient relic. The Machinati Codamus.
我把你搞砸了的咒语困在里面 一旦你完成了仪式
Trap your corrupted spell inside, once you've finished the proper ritual,
咒语便会反转 把这些人送回他们的宇宙去
will reverse the spell. And send these guys back to their universes.
然后呢
And then what?
眼睁睁看着我们灭亡吗
We perish?
不了 谢谢 我觉得还是算了
Nah. No thanks, I'll pass on that.
放我出去 彼得
Let me out of here. Peter!
斯特兰奇
Strange...
我们不能把他们送回去 至少现在不能
We can't send them back. Not yet.
为什么
Why?
这里面有的人回去就得死
Some of these guys are gonna die.
帕克
Parker...
这是他们的命运
it's their fate.
拜托 斯特兰奇 做个人吧
Come on, Strange. Have a heart.
在多元宇宙的宏大计算中
In the grand calculus of the multiverse,
他们牺牲远比他们活着更重要
their sacrifice means infinitely more than their lives.
我很抱歉 孩子
I'm sorry, kid.
如果注定如此 他们便只能死
If they die, they die.
彼得
Peter!
不要
Don't!
- 老兄 你在干嘛 彼得 赶紧走 走
Dude, what are you doing? - Peter, you gotta go. Go!
这就是我永远都不想养孩子的原因
This is why I never had kids.
把盒子给我 不
- Give me the box. - No.
Whoa!
天啊 我居然死了
Oh, my God. I'm dead.
你没死 你只是灵体分离了
You're not dead. You've just been separated from your physical form.
我的身体....什么
My physical... What?!
你怎么做到的 我也不知道
- How are you doing that? - I have no idea.
你不可能做得到这种事
You should not be able to do that.
感觉太神奇了
This feels amazing.
这可能是我有史以来经历过最酷的事情了
That might be one of the coolest things that's
但千万不要再那样做了
ever happened to me. But don't ever do that again.
放开我
Hey. Get off of me!
这是什么地方
What is this place?
由我掌控的镜像维度
The Mirror Dimension. Where I'm in control.
斯特兰奇 等一下 我们能不能好好的谈谈
Strange, stop. Can we please just talk about this?
帕克 你还没意识到
Parker, don't you realize that in the multiverse,
在多元宇宙之中
there are an infinite number of people
有无数的人知道彼得帕克是蜘蛛侠
who know Peter Parker is Spider-Man.
而咒语一旦失控 那些人就全部都会来到我们的宇宙中
And if that spell gets loose, they're all coming here.
我知道的 我明白 但我不能把他们送回去等死
Look, I know. I get it. But we can't just send them home to die.
这是他们的命 你没法改变 就像你没法改变他们的本性一样
It's their fate. You can't change that anymore than you can change who they are.
万一可以呢 也许我们可以改变他们的命运
But what if we could? What if we can change their fate?
你在干什么
What are you doing?
我是不会给你的...
I'm not giving you the...
还给我
Give me that back.
等一下 阿基米德螺旋
Wait a minute, is that an Archimedean spiral?
镜像维度只是几何学而已 你的几何学很好 你可以做几何
The Mirror Dimension is just geometry? You're great at geometry. You can do geometry.
半径先平方 再除以圆周率 再沿曲线绘制点…
Square the radius, divided by, plot points along the curve...
结束了 帕克 等事情结束以后我会回来接你的
It's over, Parker. I'll come pick you up when it's done.
嘿 斯特兰奇 你猜什么东西比魔法还酷
Hey, Strange. You know what's cooler than magic?
数学
Math.
别 千万别
Don't do this.
Oww.
我很抱歉 先生 但是..
I'm sorry, sir, but...
我必须得试试
I have to try.
老兄 发生什么事了
Dude, what happened?
我刚刚跟奇异博士打了一架 而且我居然赢了
I just had a fight with Doctor Strange and I totally won!
什么 你看 我偷了他的环戒
- What? - Look, and I stole his ring thing.
我在城里荡来荡去 然后我穿过了这个…
I was swinging through the city, and then I went through this...
超级大的镜子一样的东西
massive mirror thing,
然后我就回来了 那他去哪儿了
- and then I was back... - Where is he? Where is he?
他被我困住了
He's trapped, but...
但我不知道能困他多久
I'm not sure for how long.
你本可以任由我们自生自灭
You could've just left us to die.
为什么你不这样做
Why didn't you?
因为他不是那种人
Because that's not who he is.
我认为我可以帮到你们
I think I can help you guys.
我可以挽回在你们身上发生的一切
If I can fix what happened to you,
然后你们再回去 事情就会变得跟以前不一样了
then when you go back, things will be different
也许你们就不会因为与蜘蛛侠战斗而死
and you might not die fighting Spider-Man.
你指的挽回（治疗）是什么
What do you mean fix us?
你看 我们拥有更为先进的科技 我可以帮助你们
- Look, our technology is advanced... - I can help you.
其实我自己也算是个科学家
You know, I'm something of a scientist myself.
章鱼博士知道我的能力水平
Octavius knows what I can do.
治疗 像兽医治狗一样
Fix? You mean like a dog?
容我拒绝
I refuse.
我不能向你们保证任何事情
I can't promise you guys anything,
但至少可以让你们有活着的机会回家
but at least this way, we actually get to go home and have a chance.
第二次机会
A second chance.
这难道还不值得试一试吗
I mean, come on. Isn't that worth trying?
相信我 彼得
Trust me, Peter...
当你想治好一个人的时候
When you try to fix people,
总是要付出一些代价的
there are always consequences.
你可以不来
I mean, you don't have to come.
我还不知道你居然能说话
I also didn't know that you could talk.
但如果你选择呆在这
But if you stay here...
你还得对付那个巫师
you're gonna have to deal with the wizard.
所以 要么一起走 要么留下等死
So, we go along, or die.
说的好像我有得选一样
Not much of a choice, is it?
我只想回家
I just wanna go home.
我只是单纯的不想死
Well, I myself don't wanna be killed,
尤其是不想死在一个穿的像《龙与地下城》里面的角色一样的人手下
especially by a guy dressed like Dungeons & Dragons, so...
你的计划是什么
What's your plan?
一切尽在掌控之中
I have it all under control.
这个东西该怎么处置
What are we gonna do about this thing?
找个安全的地方放着
Well, we need to find somewhere safe for it, right?
对对对 那你保管好它
- Yeah. Yes. Yes. - You got to take it.
等一下 什么
Wait, what?
如果我发生什么不测 我就发短信给你 到时候你就按这里
If something bad happens, I'll text you, and then you just push this
然后一切就都结束了 他们也就全没了
and then it's all over, and they'll all be gone.
我们跟你一起去 不能丢下你一个人
We're going with you. We're not gonna leave you.
你们不能跟我去 太危险了 你们做的已经足够多了
You can't come with me. It's too dangerous. You guys have already done enough.
彼得 我们要齐心协力 我知道我们要齐心协力
- Peter, we're in this together. - I know we're in this together, Ned,
但如果你们陷入危险的话我是做不好这件事的
but I can't do this if I know that you're in danger.
好吗 就当是为了我 MJ 请你保管好这个
Okay? So for me, Mj please just take this.
拜托了
Please.
好 谢谢
- Fine. - Thank you.
但是彼得 我发誓 如果到时我收不到你的消息 我就会按下这个按钮
But Peter, I swear, if I don't hear from you, I'm pressing the button.
好 我真的会按的
- Sure. - Okay. And I will do it!
我们相信你 米歇尔
Yeah, we all believe you, Michelle.
这妞不可能是他的女朋友 不可能
No way that's his girlfriend. No way.
她会按的 绝对会 绝对会
- She'll do it. - Absolutely. She will.
好吧
Okay.
待会见 注意安全
- See you later. - Be safe.
你也是
You too.
Whoa.
Okay.
注意安全好吗 你也是
- Be careful, okay? - Yeah. You too.
So, uhh...
谁跟我一起来
Who's coming with me?
算我一个
Well, I'm in.
但如果出了什么差池
But, if this goes sideways...
我会把你烤个外焦里嫩
I'm gonna fry you from the inside out.
康纳斯哪儿去了 他说他想待在卡车里
- Where's Connors? - He told me he wants to stay in the truck.
报警系统已关闭
- Okay. - Alarm systems, deactivated.
Okay.
感觉有点对不起哈皮
I feel kinda bad using Happy's place like this.
没事 他不会说什么的
No, no, no, no. He'll get over it.
抱歉
Sorry.
这就是你的计划 彼得?
So this is your plan, Peter?
Mmm?
实验室没有 设备也没有 在一个公寓里你能创造出什么奇迹
No lab, no facilities, just performing miracles in a condominium?
怎么着 你打算在微波炉里煮一些油条和冷冻玉米煎饼吗
What, you're gonna cook up some churros, some frozen burritos in a microwave?
玉米煎饼我可以
I could go for a burrito.
他会把我们全杀了
He's gonna kill us all.
希望不会这样
Well, let's hope not.
你第一个 博士
You're up first, Doc.
什么 我跟你说了 我不需要治疗
What? Hey, I told you. I don't need fixing.
我不需要
I don't need fixing!
尤其是一个十几岁的孩子用一个单身汉的垃圾抽屉里的废料
Especially by a teenager using scraps from a bachelor's junk drawer.
不不不不
No, no, no, no.
后面有什么东西
He got something back there.
我能感觉得到
I can feel it.
奇怪的能量
Weird energy.
那他么是什么东西
What the hell is that?
这是一个制造者
It's a fabricator.
它可以分析 设计 建造任何东西
It can analyze, design, construct basically anything.
我以为那个是哈皮压坏的晒黑床
I thought that was a tanning bed Happy broke.
好家伙
Look at that.
他会把我们全杀了
He's gonna kill us all.
博士脖子后面的芯片
So, the chip in the back of Doc's neck
是用来保护他的大脑不受触手AI系统的侵害
was designed to protect his brain from the A.I. system
同时控制他身后的触手 但如果你仔细看
that's controlling these tentacles. But if you look here...
芯片已经烧焦了
The chip is fried.
所以不是他在控制触手
So rather than him being in control of the
而是触手在控制他
tentacles, the tentacles are now in control of him.
这也能解释为什么
Which, I guess explains why...
他看上去一直都很痛苦
he is so miserable all the time.
口渴了
Thirsty?
对 确实有点渴
Well, yes. I am thirsty.
淡水还是海水
Fresh water or salt?
你懂的 因为你是章鱼嘛
You know, because you're an octopus.
啥
What?
那就淡水吧
Fresh water it is.
看看这个地方
Look at this place.
那么多可能性
And all the possibilities.
什么 这个公寓
What? This condo?
对 公寓 我喜欢这里的平面设计
Yeah. yeah, the condo. I love the whole overfloor plan. No!
不 我说的这个世界
No, man. I'm talking about the world.
我挺喜欢现在的自己
I kinda like who I am here.
你再看看后面那个能量源 有了它我能干更多事情
And all that power back there? I could be so much more.
所以你为什么来这儿
So why did you come here?
我有个女儿
I have a daughter.
我很想见她 但在他治好我们之前
And I wanna see her. But he's not gonna send anyone home.
我们是回不去的
Till he's finished his little science project back there.
你信任他吗 我谁也不信
- You trust him? - I don't trust anyone.
话说你是怎么变成这副样子的
How'd you end up like that anyway?
我工作的地方
The place where I worked at...
正在做一个和电能有关的实验
They were experimenting with electricity
由活体生物产生电能 然后
created by living organisms, and then...
我掉进了一个装满了电鳗的生物池里
I fell into a vat of electric eels.
开什么玩笑
You're kidding.
我掉进了一个超级对撞机里
I fell into a supercollider.
靠
Damn.
看来摔倒了也得小心会往哪儿掉
Gotta be careful where you fall.
令人印象深刻
Remarkable.
这个科技 还有你
The technology and you.
等一切都结束了以后
When all this is over,
如果你想要在另一个宇宙
if you need a job and you're
找一份工作的话...
willing to commute to another universe...
成功了 完全起作用了
It worked. That totally worked!
成功了 我做到了 你能叫他上来吗
I got it. I did it. I did it. Will you send him up?
来了来了
Yup. Here we go.
对不住了 忍忍 博士
- Sorry. - Hold on, Doc.
从我来这以后就一直受尽屈辱
All of these humiliations never cease.
你 把你所谓的科学产物拿的离我远点
You! Keep your science fair project away from me!
会起作用的 有点信心
Hey, it will work. Have faith.
你个把自己变成怪物的鲁莽傻瓜也好意思说
Says the reckless fool who turned himself into a monster.
请停下来 稳住不要动
Please stop. Hold still.
你要是敢这样做的话
Don't you dare.
我发誓 等我挣脱了这个触手 我一定要...
I swear... when I get out of this wicker, I'm gonna...
博士
Doc?
章鱼博士
Doctor Octavius?
好安静...
It's so quiet...
我脑子里面的...
Those voices...
声音...
Inside my head...
我差点忘了...
I'd almost forgotten...
奥托
Otto.
在
Yes.
诺曼
Norman.
是我
It's me.
真不敢相信
Would you look at that.
我太感激你了 亲爱的 真的
I'm grateful, dear boy. Truly.
不用客气
Yeah. You're welcome.
我能帮到你吗
How can I help you?
我是彼得 请留言
This is Peter. Leave a message.
彼得 我是哈皮 我看了下我家房门旁的摄像头
Yeah, Peter, this is Happy. I accessed my doorbell camera...
那些家伙是谁
Who are those guys, huh? Is that a cyborg, you
你带了个八爪机器臂的生化人来我家
bring a cyborg with robot legs into my house?
那个家伙是泥巴变的吗 发生什么了 速速回电
One of the guys was made of mud? What's going on? Call me back.
感觉如何 诺曼
How does it feel, Norman?
你即将再次成为一个完整的个体
You're about to become whole again.
邪恶人格将不复存在
No more darker half.
只有你自己
Just you.
只有我
Just me.
好吧
Okay. Umm...
这个放在这 这个的话...
It just goes right here, this one...
这个应该能吸收更多的电能
That should be drawing power now.
我马上来检查一下 但...
I'm gonna come back in a second just to check on it, but...
注意灯光 等他们全变绿的时候
Keep an eye on the lights. When they're all green, it
就意味着你体内的电流就全部消失了
means all the electricity in your body's dissipated.
当然 并不是所有电都会消失
Well, not all the electricity.
因为人的大脑很明显需要电才能正常运作...
I mean, obviously you know you need electricity for your brain to function...
你的神经系统也是...
Your nervous system is...
我为什么要跟你普及跟电有关的这些知识
I'm not really sure why I'm explaining electricity to you.
我可以问你个问题吗 当然
- Can I ask you a question? - Sure.
这些是你的玩具
Are these your legos?
我得走了
I gotta go.
马上回来
I'll be back.
感觉不太对劲 你指哪方面
- Something feels off. - What do you mean?
我不太喜欢这样 不要管他
- I don't like this. - Leave it alone.
你们越早解决这件事 我们就能越早回家
The sooner you guys get through with this, the sooner we go home.
他在哪儿 里面
- Well? Where is he? - He's inside.
但我们现在在外面 我不是跟你说了不要跟丢吗
And yet here we are outside. Did you not hear me say don't lose him?
我需要蜘蛛侠的清晰影像
I want incriminating footage of Spider-Man.
黑暗就此展开
And so it begins.
彼得
Peter?
怎么了 我不知道
- What's wrong? - I don't know.
梅
May?
怎么了 彼得
What is it, Peter?
怎么样 彼得
What's up, Peter?
你为什么用这副表情看我
Why are you looking at me like that?
很巧妙的小技巧 你的蜘蛛感应
That's some neat trick. That sense of yours.
诺曼
Norman?
诺曼休假去了
Norman's on sabbatical.
我靠
The hell?
绿魔
Goblin.
你真的觉得我会让邪恶人格消失这种事情发生吗
No more darker half? Did you really think that I'd let that happen?
我让你夺走我的能力仅仅是因为
That I'd let you take away my power just because
你不知道真正的力量能带给你什么
you're blind to what true power can bring you?
你不认识我 是吗
- You don't know me. - Don't I?
我能看得出来她束缚了你的手脚
I saw how she trapped you.
让你为她神圣的道德使命而战
Fighting her holy moral mission.
我们不需要你来拯救
We don't need you to save us.
我们不需要治疗
We don't need to be fixed.
我们的能力不是诅咒
These are not curses.
而是上天赐予的礼物
They're gifts.
诺曼 不要
Norman, no.
安静点 狗腿子 你根本不知道你自己在说些什么
- Quiet, lapdog. - You don't know what you're talking about.
我一直在诺曼懦弱的眼睛后面观察你
I watched you from deep behind Norman's cowardly eyes.
你在挣扎 为自己想要的一切而挣扎
Struggling, to have everything you want,
但现实社会却一直在逼你做选择
while the world tries to make you choose.
而神不用做选择
Gods don't have to choose.
我们想要什么就抢什么
We take.
梅 快跑
May, run!
我的老天爷 你做了什么
Oh, my God. What have you done?
我更喜欢以前的你
I liked you better before.
上面 他在上面 是大桥上那个人
Up here! He's up there. It's the guy from the bridge.
你看见了吗
Did you see that?
放开我
Get off me!
身体强大到可以拥有一切...
Strong enough to have it all...
内心却异常的懦弱
Too weak to take it!
现在逮到你了
Now I've gotcha.
我早就跟你说过要付出代价
I told you there'd be consequences!
你的弱点 彼得...
Your weakness, Peter...
就是你的良心
is morality.
你的良心快把你噎死了
It's choking you.
你能感觉到吗
Can you feel it?
这根本没用
It didn't work.
诺曼是对的
Norman was right.
这种喜欢可怜别人的病
He got it from you. That pathetic
就是你传染给他的
sickness!
你居然想治好我...
You tried to fix me...
梅...快走...梅
May, go... May...
现在 让我来治好你
Now, I'm gonna fix you.
梅 快跑 求求你...
May, run, please...
梅
May!
彼得 彼得 彼得...
Peter, Peter, Peter...
做好事是会受到惩罚的
No good deed goes unpunished.
可以等你以后懂了再感谢我
You can thank me later.
不
No!
梅 彼得...
- May? - Peter...
梅 梅 我在这儿
May, May... I'm here.
我在这
I'm here.
你还好吗 嗯哼
- Are you okay? - Uh-huh. Uh-huh.
真的吗
Really?
Yeah.
没事的 一切都会没事的 好吗
It's okay. We're okay, right?
Yeah.
差点把头撞掉
Knocked off my head.
我也是 没伤到其他地方就好
- Yeah, me too. - That's all.
我觉得我肋骨好像断了
I think I broke my ribs.
这都是我的错 梅
This is all my fault, May.
我应该听斯特兰奇的话把他们全送回去...
I should've just listened to Strange and let him send them back...
你做的是对的
You did the right thing.
不然他们会死的
They would have been killed.
你做的是对的
You did the right thing.
这不是我的责任 梅
It's not my responsibility, May.
诺曼说什么了
What Norman said?
我的道德使命
My moral mission. No.
不 彼得 听着 听我说
No, Peter. Listen. You listen to me.
你拥有与生俱来的天赋
You have a gift.
你也有无比强大的力量
You have power.
一个人能力越大
And with great power,
责任也就越大
there must also come great responsibility.
我知道的
Yeah. I know.
我们离开这儿吧
Let's get out of here.
好 走吧
Okay, let's go.
发生什么了 你还好吗
What happened? Are you okay?
你还好 怎么了
Yeah, you're okay. What happened?
帮我...我得喘口气...
Just helps me... to catch my breath...
好 喘口气 我就在这儿
Okay. Well, catch your breath. I'm right here.
我们慢慢来
We're gonna take our time,
你深呼吸 然后...
you catch your breath, and...
然后我们带你去医院 好吗
and we'll take you to a Doctor, okay?
你还好吗
Are you okay?
来人啊 我需要一辆救护车
Somebody help. I need an ambulance.
求求了 有没有人...
Please, somebody...
怎么了
What happened?
没事的 你很好 你很好
Nothing. You're okay. You're okay.
我得...喘口气...
I'll just... catch my breath...
好 我就在这儿 我就在这儿
Okay. I'm right here. I'm right here.
我在这儿
I'm right here.
没事的
We're okay.
我在这陪着你
Just me and you.
梅
May?
你能看我一眼吗 梅 求你了
Will you look at me, May? Please?
梅 梅
May? May?
你在干什么 梅 求求你了 你醒醒跟我说说话好不好 求求你
What are you doing, May? Please, will you just wake up and talk to me, please?
彼得
Peter!
我很抱歉 我真的很抱歉
I'm sorry. I'm so sorry.
跑
Run!
一场悲剧
Tragedy.
我还能说什么
What else can I call it?
还需要说什么
What more need be said?
造成的伤害...
The damage...
破坏...
The destruction...
你自己亲眼都看见了
You saw it with your own eyes.
当人们醒来时会发现
When will people wake up, and realize
蜘蛛侠所到之处...
that everywhere Spider-Man goes...
混乱和灾难将会随之而至
Chaos and calamity ensue.
蜘蛛侠所触碰之物 皆会化为乌有
Everything Spider-Man touches comes to ruin.
而我们这些无辜的人 却被留下来收拾残局
And we, the innocents, are left to pick up the pieces.
J约拿詹姆逊 现场报道
J. Jonah Jameson, reporting.
晚安
Good night.
上帝保佑我们
And God help us all.
还是没有
Still nothing?
没有
No.
我要按了
I'm gonna press it.
什么 千万别 彼得让我们等 但是...
- What? No! - Peter told me to wait, but...
我真的要按了
I'm gonna do it.
我希望 我只希望我们能见他一面
I just wish... I just wish that we could see him.
奈德
- Ned? - Yeah?
再来一次
Do that again.
Yeah.
我只想见他一面
I just wish we could see him.
好吧
Okay...
我只想见彼得一面
I just wish we could see Peter.
Salamangkero!
你是对的 我确实会魔法
You're right. I am magic.
是他吗 是 肯定是
- Is that him? - Yeah, yeah. It has to be.
彼得 彼得 嘿 彼得
- Peter. Peter! - Hey, Peter!
彼得
Peter!
Hi. Hi!
没事的没事的 我是个好人
No, no, no. It's okay, it's okay. I'm nice guy.
Okay...
你他么是谁
Who the hell are you?
我是彼得帕克
I'm Peter Parker.
不可能
That's not possible.
我是蜘蛛侠
I am Spider-Man.
在我的世界是 然后昨天
In my world. But then, yesterday?
我就...
I was...
我就在这儿了
I was just here.
Wow.
弦理论...
String theory...
多维现实...
Multidimensional reality...
还有物质转换
And matter displacement.
都是真的
All real?
Yeah...
我就知道
Knew it!
这肯定是那个咒语的缘故
This has to be because of the spell.
咒语
The spell?
魔法咒语 不存在什么咒语
- Like magic spell? - There's no spell.
没有咒语 没有
- No spell. - No.
这里居然还有魔法
Magic's real here, too?
我的意思是... 闭嘴 奈德
- I mean.. - Shut up, Ned.
不 是假的
No, it's not real.
闭嘴 我...
- Shut up. - I mean...
有魔术师之类的东西 但没有...
There's magicians and stuff, but there's no like...
打住 打住
Stop it. Stop.
证明给我看 证明什么
- Prove it. - Prove what?
证明你是彼得帕克
That you're Peter Parker.
那我也没带身份证啊
don't carry an ID with me, you know?
带身份证这种行为不是匿名英雄的风格
Kinda defeats the whole anonymous superhero thing?
你为什么这么做
Why'd you do that?
看看你有没有一激灵
To see if you have the tingle thing.
我有一激灵 但对面包不起作用
I have the tingle thing, just not from bread.
能不能不要扔面包了 你是个非常不信任别人的人
Can you not throw the bread again? You're a deeply mistrusting person.
我尊重这一点
And I respect that.
爬爬看 爬爬看
- Crawl around. - Crawl around?
对 我不
- Yes. - No.
爬爬看 为什么要我爬爬看
- Crawl around. - Why do I need to crawl around?
因为还不足以证明你是蜘蛛侠 已经足够了
- Cause it's not enough. - This is plenty.
不够 够了
- No, it's not. - Yes, it is.
不够 粘在天花板上还不够
- Nuh-uh. - How do I stick to the ceiling?
快点
Do it.
Ned...
sabihin mo diyan sa mamang yan,
na alisin yung agiw sa sulok. Ha?
我奶奶问你能不能顺便帮他清理下那边的蜘蛛网
My Lola's asking if you could just get the cobweb there.
大概 在那儿
- It's too, like, up there? - Yeah.
谢谢
Thank you.
可以了吗
We're good?
可以了
We're good.
暂时而言
For now.
所以 我开错了传送门找错了彼得帕克
So, I opened a wrong portal to the wrong Peter Parker.
我想你可以一直这么做直到你找到正确的那个为止
Yeah, I guess you just keep doing it until you find the real one.
伤心 无意冒犯
- Ouch. - No offense.
好的
- Okay.
你能行
You're good.
找到彼得帕克
Find Peter Parker.
那个眼神和手势是怎么回事
What's with the eyes and hand?
找到彼得帕克
Find Peter Parker.
给我找到彼得帕克
Find Peter Parker!
棒极了 普通老百姓一个
Great, it's just some random guy.
哈喽
Hello.
我想我从这边跨过来应该没什么问题吧
I hope it's okay, I just came through this...
居然关了
It just closed.
你是彼得
You're Peter?
对 彼得帕克
Yeah. Peter Parker.
我之前见过你们俩...
I... I've seen you two...
Hi.
等一下 他是...
Wait. He's...
他不是你们俩的朋友...
He's not your friend...
哇噢 所以你也是蜘蛛侠咯
Whoa, it's... So you're Spider-Man too?
你为什么不早说
Why didn't you just say that?
我一般不会大张旗鼓的宣扬此事
I generally don't go around advertising it.
自吹自擂这种行为不是匿名英雄的风格
Kinda defeats the whole anonymous superhero thing.
我刚刚才说过这句话 他刚刚才说过这句话
- That's what I just said... - That's what he just said.
Ikaw, ha? Nagkalat ka nanaman.
Linisin mo lahat ng mga basura mo dito.
At ikaw? Alam mo na gusto ko itong bahay natin, maayos.
pero tingnan mo, dumi dito, dumi doon.
我奶奶问你能不能把你们刚刚射的蜘蛛网打扫干净
My Lola's asking if you could clean up the webs that you just shot.
对不起奶奶
Oh. Sorry, Lola.
当然
Yes, of course.
我要睡觉了
I'm going to bed.
晚安 奶奶
Good night, Lola.
说起来有点怪 但是...
This might seem kind of weird, but...
自从我来到这边以后我就一直在找你们的朋友
I've been trying to find your friend ever since I got here.
我有种预感...
I just had this sense that...
他需要我的帮助
That he needs my help.
我们的帮助
Our help.
他确实需要
He does.
但我们不知道他在哪儿
We don't know where he is.
And, umm...
而且说实话 我们现在是他唯一的亲人了
Honestly, right now, we're all he really has left.
好吧 有没有那种地方
Well, is there some place,
那种对他来说有特殊意义的地方
that he might go that has meaning to him?
比如...
Like a...
一个可以让他
a place where he would go to just...
远离世间所有喧嚣的地方
Get away from everything?
对我来说 是克莱斯勒大厦顶端
For me, it was the top of the Chrysler Building.
我是帝国大厦
Empire State.
景色更好
Better view.
景色确实相当好
That is a sweet view.
想起来了
Yes.
我想我知道是哪儿了
Yeah, I think I know exactly where that would be.
我想我知道在哪儿了
有些人想见你
there's some people here...
谁
Who?
嘿 等等 哇哦
Hey. Wait, wait, whoa.
我很抱歉…
Sorry...
梅姨…
About May.
很抱歉
Yeah. Sorry.
我能跟你感同身受…
I got some understanding of what you're going through...
别 千万别说你可以跟我感同身受
No, please don't tell me that you know what I'm going through.
好吧
Okay.
她死了
She's gone.
这都怪我
It's all my fault.
她死的毫无意义
She died for nothing.
我一开始就应该直接把他们送回去的
So I'm gonna do what I should've done in the first place.
- 彼得 - 请不要这样
- Peter... - Please, don't.
你不属于这 你也是 我要把你们都送回去
You don't belong here. Either of you, so I'm sending you home.
那些坏蛋来自于你们的世界 对不对
Those other guys are from your worlds, right?
所以得你们去搞定他们
So you deal with it.
他们死了也好 你们杀了他们也好
If they die, if you kill them...
都是你们自己的事
That's on you.
不关我的事
It's not my problem.
我什么都不在乎了
I don't care anymore.
我受够了
I'm done.
我很抱歉把你们牵扯进来
I'm really sorry that I dragged you into this.
但现在你们该回家了
But you have to go home now.
祝你们好运
Good luck.
我的本叔叔曾经也被杀害了
My Uncle Ben was killed.
那件事也全都是我的错
It was my fault.
我失去了…
I lost...
我失去了格温 我的…
I lost Gwen. My...
我的MJ
She was my MJ.
我没能救下她
I couldn't save her.
我一辈子都没办法原谅我自己
I'm never gonna be able to forgive myself for that.
但我得振作起来 我得…
But I carried on. Tried to...
我得往前继续走
Tried to keep going. Tried to keep being the...
我得继续做友好邻居蜘蛛侠
... friendly neighborhood Spider-Man, because
因为我知道她也会希望我能继续做蜘蛛侠
I know that's what she would have wanted.
但是
But...
在那之后 我开始…
At some point, I just...
我不会再手下留情
I stopped pulling my punches.
我变得很易怒
I got rageful.
很残忍
I got bitter.
我希望你不要变得 像我一样
I just don't want you, to end up like... Like me.
那夜我失去了本叔叔
The night Ben died,
于是我去追杀那个凶手
I hunted down the man who I thought did it.
我想要他死
I wanted him dead.
我如愿以偿了
I got what I wanted.
但这并没有让我释怀
It didn't make it better.
我反而花了更长时间去…
It took me a long time to...
去熬过那段痛苦的日子
learn to get through that darkness.
我想要他死
I wanna kill him.
我要把他碎尸万段
I wanna tear him apart.
现在我的脑海中还充斥着她的声音
I can still hear her voice in my head.
即使她已遍体鳞伤 但她仍然告诉我我们做的事是正确的
Even after she was hurt, she said to me that we did the right thing.
她告诉我能力越大
She told me that with great power...
责任越大
comes great responsibility.
等会儿 你怎么会知道这个
Wait, what? How do you know that?
本叔叔也说过
Uncle Ben said it.
在他死的那天
The day he died.
也许她并没有死的毫无意义 彼得
Maybe she didn't die for nothing, Peter.
好吧 那…
Okay, so...
康纳斯 马科 迪龙 还有…
Connors, Marko, Dillon, and...
我觉得我们可以帮迪龙和马科把那个设备修好 但其他人…
Look, I think that I can repair the devices for Dillon and Marko, but the others...
那把康纳斯交给我 我曾经治好过他一次 小事一桩
Well, I got Connors. I've already cured him once, so no big deal.
咋了 真是小事一桩
What? It's no big deal.
那太好了
Great.
确实
Yeah. That's great.
我想我们可以给奥斯本研发一个血清
I think I can make an antiserum for Doctor Osborn.
我早就想这样做了
Been thinking about it a long time.
必须把他们所有人都治好
Gotta cure all of them.
对吧
Right?
对
Right.
这是我们应该做的
That's what we do.
什么
What?
这是为你们准备的
It's for yous.
那…
So...
你是不是也有个最好的麻吉
Do you have a best friend too?
有
I did.
真有
You did?
他死在了我怀里
He died in my arms.
之前他甚至还想杀了我
After he tried to kill me.
他的死让我悲痛欲绝
It was heartbreaking.
做个诊断报告
Run a diagnostic.
好
Okay.
嘿 你没事吧
Hey, you okay?
我没事
Yeah, I'm fine.
你不该遭这个罪的
You don't deserve this.
我毁了你的人生
I ruined your life...
没有 一点也没有
Hey. No, no, no, no, no.
看着我 我陪着你的
Look at me. I'm here.
我哪儿也不去
I'm not going anywhere.
我们要一起共渡难关 同心协力共渡难关
We're gonna get through this. We're gonna get through it together.
好吗
Okay?
好
Okay.
你有女朋友吗
You have someone?
没有
No.
我没时间做彼得帕克 做自己…
I got no time for Peter Parker stuff...
你懂吗
You know?
你呢
Do you?
有一小小点… 复杂
It's a little... complicated.
我明白
I understand.
我猜我们就不是那种能过上正常人生活的人
I guess it's just not in the cards for guys like us.
对啊
Well...
但我没放弃
I wouldn't give up.
花了点时间 但是…
Took a while, but...
我和她做到了
We made it work.
- 成功了 - 对
- Yeah? - Yeah.
我和…
Me and...
MJ
MJ.
我的MJ 她…
My MJ. She, uhh...
有点乱 是不是
It gets confusing, huh?
彼得
Peter?
- 在 啊 不好意思 你说的是…
- Yeah? Oh, sorry. You mean...- Yeah? Oh, sorry. You mean...
真正的彼得
Peter-Peter.
- 我们都是彼得 奈德 - 是吧 彼得
- We're all called Peter, Ned. - Yeah. Peter?
彼得帕克
Peter Parker?
- 一样 - 我们都是彼得帕克
- Same. - We're all Peter Parker.
那台电脑
The computer!
- 我准备好了 - 我也是
- Oh, I'm ready. - Yeah, me too.
好 现在我们要做的就是把他们引到一个地方
Okay, so... Now, all we gotta do is lure these guys someplace, right?
在他们想杀了我们的同时 治好他们 并把他们送回家
Try to cure them, while they try to kill us, and then, send them home.
用那个魔法盒子
Using a magic box?
对 就是这样计划的
Well, that's the plan.
你的战服去哪儿了
So are you gonna go into battle dressed as a
还是说你就打算穿这身便装去跟他们打
cool, youth pastor, or do you got your suit?
那就好
Good.
你的蛛网弹药盒
Here's your web cartridges.
谢了 奈德
Oh, thanks, Ned.
那是用来干什么的
What's that for?
里面是蛛网液体 用来填充蛛网发射器的 为什么这么问
It's my web fluid. It's for my web shooters. Why?
- 你都是直接从你体内射出蛛网来的 - 是啊
- That came out of you? - Yeah.
- 你做不到 - 做不到
- You can't do that, huh? - No.
这到底是什么原理…
How on Earth is that...
总之 我们跑题了
Anyway, we're getting sidetracked. Look, this
这里是我们的行动地点 这里与世隔绝
is where we're gonna do this, okay? It's isolated,
就不会有无辜群众受伤了
so no one should get hurt.
我们用盒子把他们引过去 他们都想要那个盒子
We draw them there with the box, it's the one thing they all want.
但我们得先想想该怎么过去
All we have to do is figure out how we're gonna get there.
我可以开传送门
Oh, we can portal there.
- 什么 - 我现在会魔法了
- What? - I magic now.
他说的是真的 他确实会
Yeah, no, no. He's right. He can. He can.
- 我看见了 - 确实
- Yeah, we saw him. - Yeah. He is.
- 真的 - 我真的会奇异博士的魔法了
- Wait, really? - Dude, I got Doctor Strange magic.
- What? - Yeah!
还有 我向你保证
And I promise you...
我不会变成反派来追杀你的
I won't turn into a supervillain and try to kill you.
好吧
Okay...
谢了
Thank you.
Umm...
只能全力以赴了 你之前挂在嘴上那句话是什么来着
Alright. Here goes nothing. What's that thing you always say?
你期待失望…
If you expect disappointment...
不不不
No, no, no...
我们要揍他们个落花流水
We gotta kick some ass.
好
Okay.
治
Cure.
治他们个落花流水
Cure some ass.
Cure that ass.
女士们先生们
Ladies and gentlemen...
号角热线刚刚收到来电
The Bugle tip line has just received a call
是逃犯蜘蛛侠的来电
from none other than the fugitive known as Spider-Man.
在皇后区惨案不久后
Fresh from his rampage in Queens.
彼得帕克 这次你又在兜售什么有害的宣传
So, Peter Parker... What pernicious propaganda are you peddling?
- 真相 - 当然
- Just the truth. - Oh, sure.
真相是…
Truth is...
这些事全是我的错
That this is all my fault.
我意外地把那些坏人带到这里
I accidentally brought those dangerous people here.
他居然承认了
Well, he admits it!
如果你们在看的话
And if those people are watching...
我只想你们知道 我是真心想帮助你们
Just know that I really did try to help you.
我本可以杀了你们的
I could've killed you.
任何时刻都可以 但我没有
At any given moment, but I didn't.
因为我的梅姨告诉我 每个人都值得有第二次机会
Because my Aunt May taught me that everyone deserves a second chance.
这也是我来这的原因
And that's why I'm here.
你要问这是哪儿
And where is here, exactly?
一个代表第二次机会的地方
A place that represents second chances.
自由女神像 我的天 他…
The Statue of Liberty? Good God, folks! He's
又有一处国家地标建筑要毁在他手里了
about to destroy another national landmark.
全世界的观众们 如果你在看的话…
The world, if you're watching...
相信我 全世界的观众都在看
Believe me, the world is watching.
祝我好运
Wish me luck.
你的好邻居蜘蛛侠真的需要点好运
Your friendly neighborhood Spider-Man could really use some.
好了 伙计们 他们随时都会来
Okay, guys. It could be any minute now.
马上好了
Yup. Almost done.
你们知道吗 在麦克斯掉入电鳗池之前
You know, Max was like,the sweetest guy ever.
他是我遇到过的
Before he fell into a...
最贴心最好的人
pool of electric eels.
怪不得
That'll do it.
又来了...
There it goes...
你还好吗
You okay?
我的背
My back.
我猜是蛛丝荡多了搞得有点僵硬了
It's kind of stiff from all the swinging, I guess.
对噢 我的背也会疼
Oh, yeah, no, I got a middle back pain, too.
- 真的 - 是啊
- Really? - Yeah.
你想开个背吗
You want me to crack it?
Yeah.
那可太好了
That would be great.
准备好了没
You ready?
Yeah.
真舒服
That's good.
如何
How is it?
Wow.
- 太爽了 - 是吧
- That's good. - Right?
- 我感觉好多了 - 那就行
- That's better. - Yeah.
Wow.
天啊 这真的太酷了
God, this is so cool.
我一直都想拥有几个兄弟
I always wanted brothers.
所以你的体内能自然产生蛛网液体
So you could like make your own web fluid in your body?
我不想谈这个
I'd rather not talk about this.
我不是故意的…
No, I don't mean to...
- 你拿我寻开心是不是 - 没有没有 绝对没有
- Are you teasing me? - No, no, no. No, no, no.
他没有逗你 只是…
He's not teasing you. It's just that...
我们做不到 所以我们真的很好奇你的网是怎么射出来的
We can't do that, so naturally we're curious as to how your web situation works.
仅此而已
That's all.
我不想侵犯你的隐私 我只是觉得很酷
If it's personal, I don't wanna pry. I just think it's cool.
我很乐意告诉你 但我不知道怎么形容…
No. I wish I could tell you, but it's like, I don't do it...
就像…
Like I don't...
就像我不会故意去呼吸 但我一直都在呼吸
Like, I don't do breathing. Like, breathing just happens.
Whoa.
那是不是 蛛网直接从你手腕射出来
Like, does it just come out of your wrists, or...
还是哪儿都可以射出来
Does it come out off anywhere else?
只有手腕能
Only... only the wrists.
你的蛛网都用不完的吗 我的蛛网总是不够用
You never had to web block? Cause I run out of webs all the time.
所以我不得不为此建了一个实验室
I had to make my own lab.
真的很麻烦
And it's a hassle.
光听上去都很麻烦
That sounds like a hassle.
其实 事实上 就像你们说的
But I did, actually, as you said that. I was like...
- 我的蛛网也曾用完过 - 为什么
- I had a web block. - Why?
自我认知出了点问题
Existential crisis stuff.
好了 我不想再说了
Yeah, don't get me started on that.
Hey....
那你们遇到过的最疯狂的反派是什么
What are like, some of the craziest villains that you guys have fought?
你好像已经见过他们了
Seems you've met some of them.
好问题
That's a good question.
我曾经…
I fought a...
打过一个…
an alien...
黑色粘液形态的外星生物
made out of black goo once.
不是吧 我也打过外星生物
No way! I fought an alien, too.
地球上和太空中都打过
On Earth and in space.
- 噢 - 是个紫色外星人
- Oh. - Yeah. He was purple.
我也想跟外星生物打一场
I wanna fight an alien.
因为我还没…
I'm, I'm still, like...
我很惊讶你也打过外星人的 还是在太空里
That you fought an alien, in Space.
相比之下我就逊爆了
I'm lame.
我曾经打过一个…
Like, I fought a Russian guy in a...
驾驶着巨型犀牛机甲的俄罗斯人
Like a rhinoceros machine.
能不能谈回“我很逊”这个话题
Hey, can we rewind it back to the "I'm lame" part?
老实说 你一点也不逊
'Cause, you are not.
谢谢你 真的 我没事 我没说我很逊
Aw, thanks. No, yeah. I appreciate it, I'm not saying I'm lame.
只是自言自语而已
But it's just the self-talk maybe we should, you know...
- 听着 - 拜托
- Yeah, listen... - Please...
我觉得你很神奇
You're... You're Amazing.
你吸收一下
Just to take it in for a minute.
- 行行行 - 你真的很神奇
- Yeah, yeah, yeah. - You... You are amazing.
- 应该吧 - 你真的很超凡
- I guess I am. - You are amazing.
- 谢谢 - 你能说一遍吗
- Thank you. - Will you say it?
不 我其实挺需要点鼓励的 谢谢你
No, I kinda needed to hear that. Thank you.
好了伙计们 专心点 你们感觉到了吗
Alright guys, focus up. Can you feel that?
Yeah.
过得如何 彼得
What's up, Peter?
你觉得这个新消息怎么样
How do you like the new news?
你把那个盒子给我 让我毁了它
Look, you give it to me, I'm gonna destroy it.
我就放你一马
But I'll let you live.
不要逼我下杀手 彼得
Don't make me a murderer, Peter.
好了 他们来了
Okay, guys. Here it comes.
嗨 麦克斯
Hey, Max!
我可想你死你了
I missed you, man!
MJ 当心点
All right, MJ, heads up!
明白了 把传送门关了
Got it! Close it.
- 这… - 我知道
- Okay... - I know.
- 为什么关不掉 - 我不知道 我…
- Why isn't it closing? - I don't know... I...
你之前没关过吗
Have you closed before? No?
没有啊 我只开过
No. I mean I have opened some.
亲爱的麦克斯 我们好好的谈谈如何 就我俩
Max, Max, Max. Can we just talk for a second? Just you and me, just...
看看谁来了 我们的老朋友蜘蛛侠
Look who showed up! Our old friend Spider-Man.
我本来想救你的
I'm trying to save you, Max. That's all I've ever wanted.
- 你从来没想过要救我 - 我有
- You're not trying to save me. - I am.
你现在对我来说屁都不是
You ain't even shit no more.
不用你担心 我不需要你来拯救
Don't worry about me. I'll save myself.
我吸引他的注意力了 然后呢
I got his attention, now what?
打开笼子
Open the cage!
那个蜥蜴人也在这
Just FYI, Lizard-guy is here too.
伙计们 检查通讯 哈咯
Guys, comm check, hello.
我需要麦克斯的解药
I need Max's cure.
马上来
Yeah. I'm on it.
彼得 我需要蜥蜴人的解药
Peter! I need the Lizard cure.
马上 马上
Okay! Okay!
盒子哪儿去了 彼得
Where's the box, Peter?
- 弗林特 我们可以帮助你们所有人 - 我才不在乎
- Flint! We can help everyone. - I don't care!
抱歉
Sorry!
我跟你说过了 沙人 我们都回不去了
I tried to tell you, Sandman. Nobody's going home.
刚刚他么的发生了什么
What the hell, is going on out there?
我一直在叫你 彼得2号彼得2号
I kept yelling at you, Peter 2, Peter 2...
我听见了 但我以为你才是彼得2号
I know, but I thought you're Peter 2?
什么 我不是彼得2号…
What? I'm not Peter...
你们俩别吵了 都听彼得1号的
Stop arguing, both of you! Listen to Peter 1.
很明显我们很不擅长团队合作
Look, we're clearly not very good at this!
我知道我知道 糟透了
I know, I know. We suck.
我真的不知道该怎么与人合作
I, I don't know how to work as a team.
我也是
Me neither.
我知道 我在团队里待过
Well I do. I have been in a team, okay?
我不想自吹自擂 但我真的待过
I don't wanna brag, but I will.
- 我曾经在复仇者联盟待过 - 复仇者联盟
- I was in the Avengers. - The Avengers?
- 对 - 那可太棒了
- Yeah. - That's great!
- 谢谢 - 复联是什么
- Thank you. - What is that?
等等 你们的世界没有复联
Wait, you don't have the Avengers?
是乐队吗 你玩乐队
Is that a band? Are you in a band?
不 不是乐队
No, I'm not in a band. No, the Avengers is a...
- 复联是地球上最强大的… - 有什么用
- Earth's Mightiest... - How is this helping?!
好吧 那不重要 重要的是我们得专注 相信你的直觉
Look, it's not important. All we gotta do is focus, trust your tingle,
彼此打好配合 好吗
and coordinate our attacks, okay?
先选好一个目标
Yes. Okay. Let's pick one target.
Right.
我们一个一个的解决他们
We take them off the board one at a time.
现在你明白了 好
Now you got it. Okay...
- 彼得1号 彼得2号 - 彼得2号
- Peter 1, Peter 2... - Peter 2.
- 彼得三号 - 彼得3号
- Peter 3. - Peter 3!
- 好 一起上吧… - 等会儿 等会儿
- All right, let's do this... - No, wait, wait, wait, wait!
我爱你们
I love you guys.
谢了
Thank you.
- 好了 一起上吧 - 冲
- All right. Let's do this. - Let's go.
蜘蛛侠们
Okay, Spider-Man.
首先对付沙人
Sandman first.
我去把他引进女神像里面
I'm gonna lead himinside the statue.
我们顶上见
I'll meet you at the top.
- 嗨 康纳斯博士 - 嗨 彼得
- Hey, Dr. Connors. - Hello, Peter.
彼得1号
Peter 1!
收到
I got it.
弗林特 我们是想帮助你
Flint! We're trying to help you!
伙计们 我到顶部了
Guys, I'm at the top!
我需要解药
I need the cure!
来了 来了 来了
I'm coming, I'm coming, I'm coming!
我马上回来
I'll be right back.
没事了 弗林特
It's okay, Flint.
我们会送你回家的
We're gonna get you home.
先…待着别乱跑
Just... stay right here.
我们该怎么阻止他 我从来没见过他这么这么强大过
How do we stop him? I've never seen him this powerful.
是方舟反应器 我们得从他身上把它摘下来
It's the arc reactor. We gotta get it off him.
你们别想从我身上夺走它
You're not gonna take this away from me.
行不通的
That's not gonna work.
好吧 看来我们得一起靠近他
Okay, we've gotta do this up close.
彼得2号打右路 彼得三号跟我打左路
Peter 2 go right, Peter 3 go left. On me.
没事 我们再试一次 不要放弃
All right, we're gonna do it again. We're just gonna keep trying.
我们能行 我能行
Alright. We got it. I got it. Got this.
关闭传送门
Close the portal.
噢 不不 不好
Oh, no. No, no, no!
奈德 那是蜥蜴人 我们应该…
Ned, that is a lizard, and we should...
快跑
Run!
康纳斯 站住
Connors, stop!
Yeah.
别管他们 他们是我的
Leave them. They're mine.
我不需要你的帮助 我自己能行
I don't need your help. I got it just fine.
章鱼博士 不要
Dr. Octavius. No.
你在干什么
What are you doing?
放开我
Get it off me!
轻轻松松
There you go.
MJ!
- Okay. Right, right, right.
他去哪儿了
Where is he?
等等
Wait, wait, wait!
先生 奇异博士 在你动手之前
Before you do anything, Mister--- Doctor Strange, sir, well...
彼得的计划奏效了
Peter's plan is working.
- 什么计划 - 他在治愈他们
- What plan? - He's curing them.
康纳斯博士
Dr. Connors?
欢迎回来 先生
Welcome back, sir.
真是活见鬼了
Well, I'll be damned.
你刚刚是不是开了扇传送门
Did you just open a portal?
是的 先生 确实是我
Yes, yes, sir. I did.
麦克斯
Max.
Max...
没事了
Don't worry.
- 我没电了 被抽的一干二净 - 你确定
- I'm out. Empty. - You sure about that?
我又变回一个无名小卒了
I'm back to being a nobody.
- 你从来都不是无名小卒 麦克斯 - 不 我是 我是
- You were never a nobody, Max. - Yes, I was. Yes, I was.
这样说那我也算无名小卒
You don't see me.
我能跟你说件事吗
Can I tell you something?
Yeah.
你长得挺帅的 像个小孩一样
You got a nice face. You're just a kid.
你来自皇后区
You're from Queens...
你有战袍
You got that suit...
你帮助他人
You helping out people...
我以为你会是个黑人
I just thought you was gonna be black.
很抱歉 我不是
Oh, man. I'm sorry.
别在意 我想在其他宇宙肯定也有黑人蜘蛛侠
Don't mind it. There's gotta be a black Spider-Man somehwere out there.
该死的电鳗
Goddamn eels.
太阳的能量
The power of the sun...
尽在我掌中
... in the palm of your hand.
彼得
Peter?
奥托
Otto.
很高兴见到你 小伙子
Oh, it's good to see you, dear boy.
我也是
It's good to see you.
你都已经这个年纪了
You're all grown up.
你过得如何
How are you?
努力变得更好
Trying to do better.
斯特兰奇 慢着
Strange, wait...
我被你吊在大峡谷晃了快十二个小时
I've been dangling over the Grand Canyon for twelve hours!
我知道 我知道
I know. I know, I know, I know. I...
我非常抱歉 先生
I'm sorry about that, sir. I mean...
你去大峡谷了
You went to the Grand Canyon?
- 你本来可以帮他的 - 不 没事的 没事的
- He could've used your help. - No, no. It's okay, it's okay.
见见我的新朋友 这是彼得帕克
These are my new friends. This is Peter Parker,
这也是彼得帕克 蜘蛛侠 蜘蛛侠
he's Peter Parker. Spider-Man, Spider-Man.
他们都是从其他宇宙来帮忙的
They're mes from other universes. They're here to help.
这位就是我跟你们提到过的巫师
This is the wizard that I was telling you about.
听着 我觉得你愿意给他们第二次机会真的让我印象深刻
Look, I am really impressed that you managed to give them all a second chance, kid.
但现在该做个了结了
But this has to end, now.
蜘蛛侠愿意出来跟我玩玩吗
Can the Spider-Man come out to play?
斯特兰奇 不要
Strange, no!
你还好吗
Are you okay?
我还好
Yeah. I'm okay.
你还好吗
Are you okay?
谢谢你 斗篷先生 谢谢
Thank you, Mister Cape, sir.
奈德
Ned!
MJ!
彼得
Peter?
- 奈德 - 彼得
- Ned! - Peter?
Hey.
- 你们还好吗 - 还好
- Are you okay? - We're okay.
可怜的彼得
Poor Peter.
懦弱至极 都没胆送我去死
Too weak to send me home to die.
那我就只好送你去死
I just wanna kill you myself.
Attaboy.
当时她在那儿
She was there.
这是不是意味着...
It doesn't mean...
我对她下手了
I may have struck the blow.
那你呢
But you?
你才是害死她的凶手
You are the one that killed her.
彼得
Peter?
我到底做了什么
What have I done?
- 是你 - 你没事吧
- It's you. - You okay?
我没事 但我有过这种经历
Yeah, I'm good. I've been stabbed before.
Hey.
接的不错
Hey, nice catch.
你看见没
You saw?
这是真的吗 还是我快死了
Is that happening? Or am I dying?
- 我得走了 - 我能搞定
- I gotta go. - Yeah. Yeah, I got him.
发生什么了
What's happening?
他们开始不断的传送过来 我挡不住了
They're starting to come through and I can't stop them.
一定有办法的 你能不能再施个咒
There's got to be something we can do. Can't you just cast a spell again?
就像我搞砸那次一样
Like the original way. Before I screwed it up.
太迟了 他们已经到了
We're too late for that. They're here.
他们全是冲你来的
They're here because of you.
那如果让所有人都忘记我呢
What if everyone forgot who I was?
什么
What?
他们冲我来的 对不对
They're coming here because of me, right?
冲彼得帕克来的对不对
Because I'm Peter Parker? So cast a new spell.
那这次你就施一个让所有人都忘记彼得帕克是谁的咒
But this time, make everyone forget who Peter Parker is.
让所有人都忘…
Make everyone forget...
忘了我
Me.
别
No.
行得通的 对吗
But it would work, right?
是 确实行得通
Yeah, it would work.
但你得明白 所有人 包括认识你的人和爱你的人
But you got to understand, that would mean everyone, who knows and loves you
我们都…
We'd...
我们关于你的所有记忆都会消失
We'd have no memory of you.
仿佛你这个人从来没存在过一样
It'll be as though you never existed.
我明白
I know.
施咒吧
Do it.
那你趁现在去跟他们道别吧 没多少时间了
Then go and say your goodbyes. You don't have long.
谢谢你 先生
Thank you, sir.
叫我斯蒂芬
Call me Stephen.
谢谢你 斯蒂芬
Thank you, Stephen.
Yeah...
感觉还是怪怪的
Still feels weird.
我们有缘再见了
I'll see you around.
再见 孩子
So long, kid.
差不多了 你们是时候回家了
I think this is it. I think you're about to go home.
但我…
But I... uhh...
谢谢你
Thank you.
我只是想…
I just wanted...
我想告诉你…
I wanna tell you that...
但我不知道该怎么说…
I really don't know how to say this, like...
彼得
Peter.
我想让你知道…
I want you to know that I...
你懂的
You know.
这是我们的宿命
It's what we do.
对 我们的宿命
Yeah. It's what we do.
好了 我得去找MJ和奈德了
Right. I gotta find Ned and MJ.
谢谢你 谢谢你们 真的谢谢你们
Thank you. Thank you. Thank you. Thank you!
那就这样了
I guess I'll see you.
- 注意安全 - 再见
- Keep safe. - Bye.
你真的很痛苦 不是吗
You're in so much pain, huh?
- 是
- I am. - Yeah.
你们还好吗
Are you okay?
我们没事
Yeah, we're okay.
喔 我的天啊 你在流血
Oh, my God. You're bleeding.
- 不 我没事 - 你确定吗
- No. I'm okay. - Are you sure?
我保证 我真的没事
I'm fine. I promise.
我们得走了 是吗
We should go, right?
你们将会彻底忘了我
You're gonna forget who I am.
- 什么 - 彼得 你在说什么
- What? - Peter, what are you talking about?
没事的
It's okay...
之后我会来找你们的
I'm gonna come and find you,
然后跟你们解释清楚所有事
and I'll explain everything.
我会让你们想起来的
I'll make you remember me.
就仿佛这些事从来没有发生过
It'll be like none of this ever happened.
好吗
Okay?
万一我想不起来怎么办
But what if that doesn't work?
万一不管用 万一我真的记不起你了怎么办
What if that doesn't work, what if we can't remember you?
我不想那样
I don't wanna do that.
我真的不想
我知道的 MJ 我知道的
I know. MJ, I know.
一定有其他办法的
There's gotta be something we can do.
我们想其他办法好不好 肯定有其他选择的
We can come up with like a plan or something? There's gotta be something we can do.
这是唯一的办法了
There's nothing we can do.
没事的
But we'll be okay.
你保证
Promise?
我保证
Yeah, I promise.
我会来找你的 好吗
I'll come find you. Okay?
我知道你一定会的
I know you will.
你最好不要食言
You better.
我保证有办法挽回的
I promise I'll fix this.
我真的好恨魔法
I really hate magic.
我也是
Yeah. Me, too.
我爱你
I love you.
我爱你…
I love you...
你发誓 当我们再见面时你会跟我们解释一切
Swear that, you will tell me if we meet again.
距离自由女神像惨案发生已经过去数周了
It's been a few weeks since the fiasco on the Statue of Liberty,
匿名义警蜘蛛侠的支持者们一直声称
and Spider-Man's cultists continue to contend
他是一个真正的英雄
that the vile vigilante is a hero.
但他要真是英雄的话 他为什么不摘下面具告诉我们他的真实身份呢
But if he were a hero, he'd unmask himself and tell us who he really is.
因为他只是一个隐藏自己身份的懦夫
Because only a coward conceals his identity.
只有懦夫才会隐藏他们真实的一面
Only a coward hides his true intentions.
稍事休息后 将为你揭开…
Rest assured, ladies and gentlemen, that this reporter will uncover those...
嗨
Hi.
我叫彼得帕克 你不认识我 但我…
My name is Peter Parker. You don't know me, but I...
我是彼得帕克 你还不认识我 但…
My name is Peter Parker and you don't know me, but...
好吧…
Okay...
嗨
Hi.
有什么需要吗
Can I help you?
你好…
Hi. Umm...
我叫彼得帕克
My name is Peter Parker.
我…
And I...
我想要杯咖啡 谢谢
would like a coffee. Please.
好啊 没问题 彼得帕克
Okay, no problem, Peter Parker.
给我的工程师伙计来个甜甜圈
Donuts for my fellow engineer.
- 等等 什么 - 麻省理工的工程师
- Wait, what? - MIT, they have the engineers.
噢 对对对 我应该知道的
Oh, right, right, right. I should probably know that.
看你长的就像麻省理工的
Look at you with the school spirit.
彼得帕克
Peter Parker?
你的咖啡
Your coffee.
噢 谢谢
Right. Thank you.
要去麻省理工了 你激动吗
Are you excited for MIT?
当然
Right. Yeah.
有点奇怪 但事实上我也挺激动的
Yeah, actually I am excited, which is weird
因为基本上也没什么事能让我激动了
because I don't really get excited about things.
我甚至有点期待失望
I kind of expect disappointment.
因为这样你就永远都不会失望了
'Cause then you'd never actually be disappointed.
对吗
Right?
没错
Yeah. Right.
我只是… 我不知道
It's just... I don't know...
出于某些原因 这次感觉有点不太一样
It just kinda feels different this time for some reason.
就很…
That was...
你没事吧
You okay?
已经不疼了
Doesn't really hurt anymore.
还有其他事吗
Is there anything else?
没了
No.
谢谢你
Thank you.
没问题
No problem.
下次见
See you around.
你是怎么认识她的
How do you know her?
因为蜘蛛侠
Through Spider-Man.
- 你呢 - 我也是
- You? - Same.
前段时间我失去了一个很好的朋友
I lost a good friend a while back.
就是这个感觉
It felt like this.
失去他们让我很伤心
Hurts cause they're gone,
之后想起他们代表了什么意味着什么以后 就更让人伤心了
and then it hurts all over again because you remember what they stood for,
然后你就会想…
and you wonder...
失去的就永远失去了吗
Is all that gone too?
不 还没有
No, it's not gone.
所有接受过她帮助的人…
Everybody she helped...
都会继续前行
they'll keep it going.
你真这样想的吗
You really think so?
我就知道
I know it.
照顾好你自己 好吗
Take care of yourself, okay?
我会的 很高兴认识你
Yeah. Nice to meet you.
Okay...
我想我明白了 你是说这个世界…
Okay, I think I got this. You're saying that this whole place here...
到处都是…
It's just tons of...
超能力者
Superpeople.
他已经重复这句话快一小时了
And he has been saying it for hours.
好吧 再给我捋一遍 抱歉我实在是太笨了
All right, tell me again. I'm sorry. I'm an idiot.
首先有个穿着锡制战袍 飞来飞去的亿万富翁
There was a billionaire. He had a tin suit, and he could fly. Right?
然后是一个异常暴躁浑身绿色的家伙
Okay. And there was a really angry green man.
- 浩克 - 浩克
- Hulk. - Hulk.
然后你觉得致命守护者这个名字很蠢
And you thought Lethal Protector was a shit name.
确实很蠢
Yeah, because it is.
那再跟我讲一遍关于那个有石头收集癖的紫皮外星人
Now, tell me again about your purple alien that loves stones.
因为据我了解 外星人 他们一点也不喜欢石头
'Cause I'll tell you what, man. Aliens, they do not love stones.
埃迪 差不多得了
Eddie, don't start!
你猜外星人真正喜欢什么 喜欢吃脑子
You know what aliens love? Eating brains!
因为这是外星人的本性 懂吗
Because that's what they do. All right?
先生 那个外星人把我全家都弄失踪了
Senor, he made my family disappear.
失踪了整整五年
For five years.
五年
Five years?
真够久的
That's a long time.
我觉得 我是不是该去纽约找这个...
I mean, maybe I should go to New York and speak to this,
叫蜘蛛侠的人谈谈
Spider-Man.
埃迪 我们已经醉了
Eddie! We are drunk!
- 我们去裸泳吧 - 我才不要去裸泳
- Let's go skinny-dip! - I don't think we should skinny-dip.
该买单了 先生
Sir, you have to pay your bill.
发生什么事了 不
What is happening? No!
他就这么跑了
And there he goes.
单没买 小费也不给
Without paying the bill, no tips, nothing.